thought plugins the plot thickens
[Laughter]
we're in now we have to put our put our
face on and be serious have to put our
we have to put our coffee shop mask on
Oh what is that we're just talking about
coffee shop maths
welcome to the junk Arab podcasts which
I'm spontaneously calling it right now
Jessica fall it's that way to have you
Jessica fought lovely to have you had to
rerecord that because she punched the
mic I had to edit it out so I was
telling that my time is important she's
already ruining it well I was turning
like a radio show host I said I'm
addicted roasted yes let's start there
though with the the coffee shop face so
I was as I said weird we were just
talking and I were talking about how you
can't really turn off the if you work in
retail for example you can't wait to
turn off the retail face anymore if you
live in your hometown or you live around
people that you may see while you're
working you have to do the Hey how are
you today you know even if you haven't a
terrible day like and so you work here
you're your bartender you've worked in
multiple places like you're 40 coffee
shops like as you've been doing a degree
like so you've you know how this is like
so can you talk about like the mass that
we have to put on and the importance of
let's say being able to turn it off or
recognize it wearing the mask I think I
would say like I I constantly feel like
wherever I'm going
whatever I'm doing I'm really kind of
like not always me I have to be very
cautious tough to be very happy I've
been I mean yummy to speak on like I was
in social work and then I was also a
bartender and so I have met various
types of the community I've also worked
in the schools to to add on to that so
yeah like I bet you'd like to be around
it like you've had to keep a face up of
like just in case people see me I've got
to make sure I do this right you've had
a role model it seems like I think
that's kind of what I've be a role model
make sure that other people
can see you being nice and being a good
you know right that's kind of been
ingrained in me too but well do you
think I mean it gets I think it gets
thrown into the category of role model
but it's I think it's something else
it's like because you aren't really able
to be yourself at all times and not
saying like of course like don't go to a
charity event and get hammered like I'm
not saying that I'm just saying like
when you're not able to feel as if you
can ever go outside without shirt and
tie on or you don't feel that you can
you know get a little loose and have a
drink with your friends on the weekend
just in case you run into someone that
you work with or works at a company that
you've dealt with like like that I think
that's a little different than keep
keeping being who you are and being a
role model it seems like it's kind of a
little different of a path yeah I think
it's partly like me thinking I I need to
be a role model but I also think it's
everyone asking me to be right but I
don't maybe nobody is no but I have
nobody's ever really said like do you
have this right and you can't be like
this like no one's ever said that to me
dude it's it's that thing like we think
that we know what everybody's thinking
about us at all times like I can't be
drunk because I know that if I see
Stephanie like I babysat her kid and
she's gonna tell Tiffany and it's like
these crazy mazes that we create for our
reasonings but like now that I'm
actually I'm kicking back a little bit
further I'm taking a little deeper the
other thing is like no you didn't where
is it you're kicking back a little bit
further talking about Society math this
is cool stuff that I can edit out yeah
yeah so this is like the essence this is
like our training to TED talk oh yeah
right okay so we were talking about
wearing masses where we started and we
were talking about today about child
childhood so disappointment
disappointment what do you mean by
disappointment um I grew up without my
dad was not someone who like my dad
didn't spank me but really didn't get in
trouble a lot because I was a very
mindful child for the most part but I my
dad I knew when he was upset because he
would be disappointed he would never be
like angry was heavy right yeah and so I
think I don't want to disappoint so I
don't want it
want to work for someone and help them
build up their whole life or you know be
a the fun part of though whatever
however I help them I don't want to be a
disappointment to them if they ever
found out like hey you helped me through
my drug addiction but now I see you out
here right getting drunk and like you're
your C but that's the thing is like
because they don't know I mean that
that's thing is like if they walk by you
and see that they're like oh great like
that person whatever but for all they
know like you've had this revelation and
you're like you you're not an alcoholic
or you know whatever like you're
actually Jillian joint like you're doing
so great you're having a celebration
with your friends like they see it as
like great you you Marty yeah you're
partying but like that's the thing like
it is I think what I'm pointing at is
that we don't [__] know we never know
like we don't ever know what people are
really going through but so because of
that our defense tactic as like societal
beings now is we created a mask like we
created here's you need to pretend to be
just in case they start thinking some
bad things like if you don't want them
to think that you're actually this or
actually know the real things so let's
do this we're stuck in everything in my
life is obviously not everything my
life's going great
and I'm really good at this because that
let's let's leave this one into social
media yeah wait pause right there
because I didn't hit record on either of
the videos I want challenges asked an
audio engineer I want challenges like I
need to go back to edit like how do I
make that sound good yeah because I want
like when I create music like looking at
the next 60 years of my life I literally
want to create music like with my mouth
and like I want to go out and take a
whole day just sample [__] in the
environment and like edit it so editing
sound yeah like being like coming from a
DJ background first and going into audio
engineering and like producing ish or
whatever the [__] it is that I've been
doing like I'm able to do like the
sample thing of like taking other sounds
from other people and then making them
my own right you know that's cool
that's something you really have to know
- that's like an ear you have to learn
you don't just have it I mean sometimes
you do you have a knack for yeah again
you're like trained - yeah I mean that's
the thing
I think there there are some people like
just less there's like different species
like I was saying I was like we're all
completely different yes for him and so
we're different like there's some people
who do have and maybe are born with like
innate talent like that's there's no
doubt about it like when a [__]
kid can play piano at 3 years old is
crazy like yeah but it's also our
ability to learn at different ages is
very different in our ability to like
accept new knowledge in order to learn
at different ages yes very different so
I think talent yes there are many people
are born a talent but I'm kind of
discovering that you anybody can learn
anything the length of the time that it
takes you to learn it is just based off
of where you are at in life right and a
lot of people don't don't get the
opportunity to always adapt because
they're living in an environment yeah
yeah exactly like your environment is
pretty much [__] everything like what
our environments are like we want to be
like oh I was born like this and like
dude even like weight and stuff like are
literally people pick up their mom's
eating habits like that's this is never
out been outside of that they've never
stepped outside or looked outside yeah
no one's ever told them maybe you should
do something different yeah I know and
we want it we don't want to say that
we're wrong either and so we go up and
we live our whole life's and that's what
we do now that's who we are and we
solidify it by saying my mom did this so
I got to do it too cuz genetics right
because if we have like a great
understanding of how genetics work any
of us yeah this theory that like our
memories and the way that we were raised
like you and I were raised in homes that
were a little bit different than the
typical you know yeah one parent that
you were raised in a circus with clowns
most of the time yeah monkeys I would
say monkeys yeah anyway I have a theory
that like we learned to look outside
because we had to at a younger age
we went through some like I could call
it trauma but I wouldn't I wouldn't
identify with my childhood as a
traumatic but there were events that
caused me to have to learn differently
or quicker or about a situation or some
kind you know any me like a little bit a
little too intelligent for my
and I learned things that we shouldn't
have seen exactly and then I think when
it comes to adulthood now I'm thinking
those those kids are those people who
were raised and you know these really
crazy environments for a child yeah you
know this normal whatever it is we were
we're now able to like look outside and
and be really way more aware because
we've our whole life had to be more
aware mm-hmm we can take a childhood
perspective and inspect it from an adult
intelligence yeah somehow somehow yeah I
mean that's the thing is we we make up
our own meanings and it's not like we're
born knowing what the [__] that means
yeah like we're I mean we're born with
like if we didn't have language like we
wouldn't know anything we would be
stupid monkeys like like we have
language as our baseline and then from
there we learn like how it is to be and
yeah we we've adapted just different I
suppose yeah because there is the the
really
unfortunately naive group of our age
people who are naive or who they have
followed through on this normal path you
know they've done what they're supposed
to be doing they thought right yeah and
they were led by two parents who did the
same thing who fell into the same you
know I don't know it's I well so I think
it's kind of a kind of a stretch but
I've actually been thinking about this I
think we want blame so much or we want
or where we're thinking again we're
thinking that the person is going to
blame us or what they really mean is
that we're bad parents I think what
we're actually discovering like with
like all this information that our age
you and I are able to intake now like we
are able to very intelligently discover
that like who that the things that
happened when we were younger did
actually kind of just because we're it's
been taken from us but traumatized us
right like we like you could be deathly
afraid of snakes not because you were
bitten by a snake when you were two but
when you were three and a half there
was a guy who kind of like looked at you
and weird and you were in a bad mood and
he was wearing a snake shirt like that's
how delicate our brains really are yeah
in like that isn't something that needs
blame on like our parents you know how
to raise us like what the [__] they did
they were eating they were just
experiencing like the greatest time in
their life because they're like addition
introducing TV and they're introducing
sugar and whatever like they were just
living the dream and they're they're in
there
we had a religion base still kind of
like system of values alright so our
parents even if they weren't religious
they kind of said like okay here's
here's what we're and teach them wrong
and right whatever but like we're
discovering now because we're so
intelligent now our age people that
sounds cocky but like we know a lot yeah
so we now know that all these things
that make up who we think we are who we
are who we who others think we think we
are are we've we've [__] that up a
little bit like yeah like we've kind of
like [__] each other up like we like
parents accidentally kind of [__] us
up we yeah we like kids that are our age
like like there's people that are our
age that are accidentally maybe [__]
their kids up now and that's just that's
just the way that I talk saying [__]
up that sounds terrible but they're just
like I'm just saying we don't know we
don't know and I think that what I'm
saying is the things that I've been
learning lately and things that you've
been learning lately it seems that like
we can be like reprogram like it does
not anyways fall but we yeah like we're
life you can be changing as long as you
keep active and amazing you know
creating those like we talked about
earlier creating the connections and the
synopsis in your brain are telling you
like okay this is okay to learn you know
like forget this because this seems to
work better don't you think like
learning things yeah they're hard but
like there's a reason that your body
keeps trying or your brain yeah you know
if you choose I guess maybe that's it
it's the choice you make yeah what
learning seems to be like like when you
stop learning I feel like nobody ever
wants to admit that they have stopped
learning though and there was a long
time where like I would tell you that
I've been learning this I'm learning
that and I really wasn't
much I was just kind of wasting my time
on social media or kind of just like
filling in the blanks with like too much
other people's stories and calling that
learning yeah other people's opinions
are calling out learning now that I'm
learning things firsthand and like
really diving in like watching lectures
and [__] like that like I actually feel
fulfilled and as if I'm growing and I'm
making new neurological connections like
I'm actually understanding things that
are happening so do you think like not
being willing to change must have some
adverse effects it so like I think what
we're maybe for lack of it les do you
think maybe we're waking up to the fact
that like I think I want to call this
for you I know because I keep yeah lacy
keeps using that term for me and it's a
good time I have these like revelations
where I'm like you almost blew your own
mind just now the conversation you just
had no no I know and that's that's what
I'm talking about the essence of that
it's what I'm talking about yeah that
you your brain continues to be able to
grow and yeah all the time
yeah but because you've fired that in
your brain you've chosen that because
your whole life has been a series of
that's gonna be hard when that was hard
but I got a little bit mm-hmm okay all
the all the times there's got to be a
finite number of times that you think
your [__] world is crumbling down and
this is it yeah and you wake up the next
day and you're like ah well [__] I guess
I got another I did okay like I thought
that I did bad but I'm literally still
here
like there's got to be a finite number
of times that that can happen before
your friend like okay [__] I think that
maybe that little voice that is telling
me to like just stay above water I
should listen to that yeah and when
follow it when a boat comes along like I
should put my [__] hand on the side
of it and check it out and like
investigate yeah like I think I think
that's like a lot of people who you know
are speakers and a lot of people who
like are able to indicate
like the thoughts like this a lot of
times they haven't gone through
traumatic experiences like because
they've been hit a lot I guess they
realized that like oh we're not me
we're not right we can be hit and like
where I got hit I can actually like say
like what is that about not like oh
don't look at that ever I can say what
is that yeah and then I could look at
other people and say hey I have that
same [__] thing the same thing that
the same thing [__] hit me like a
look at try this and then they can go oh
[__] and then they could teach their
kids and we're like I think it's just I
think that's literally how knowledge and
growth as humanity is supposed to work
but you just took that from like it that
was it really cool how I read that I'm
sorry to hijack it
I didn't mean to answer no no no I'm I'm
glad that you said that you literally
brought it from like you could have we
just had the conversation of how when
you learn as a child it's because your
parents are repeating what they learned
so then you spoke about oh this happened
to me and I'm gonna say hey I learned
how to take care of this because I saw
this once when you're trying to help
somebody else who got here precisely
meteor
you know this what look like yeah it's a
hand meaning yeah but you win you win
optimist on that where you said like
thank you we can use these well I know
but you know we can use these same
things that we're sitting here saying
like this is the challenge this is why
we are the way we are you just there was
a solution there by having optimism and
saying like yeah not only so we can
repeat these things but we can repeat
these things positively right to
encourage change versus to encourage
nothing at all you know yeah so yeah so
that's funny that's so so I think we
just did for me as you pointed out the
way the way that I found a way out of a
hole I guess like literally like so you
pointed out that I actually pointed out
that I blue printed the way out
well you did well I blue painted excuse
me
the way that you could start to the way
that you chose to end I mean yeah i okay
yes I'm sorry I'm still just taking this
I'm sorry um the same thing we're
talking about like people who have been
through like through childhood like
maybe like some more rougher it's not
like your typical like we didn't have
that much crazy stuff go on like that's
our way of
lost it no okay okay I could have found
it so I've been okay so by working a
lifepro tip instead of saying I lost it
out loud Mike don't ever say that and
just sit with it and sit in silence so
I've been watching a lot of monks
instead for that yeah I'm not kidding
like I've been watching a lot of monks
and like like meditation guy doesn't
stuff and there's times where old me
would have been so impatient but now I'm
able to sit through and like they're
explaining something and they stop for
like 15 seconds and like instead of
saying nope I lost it
I think we live except that we have lost
it yeah we focus more there's only one
spot for this thing
there's nothing one spot for this thing
and if we put I lost it in that spot
then this definitely goes away yeah so
when you say I lost it out loud also I
think that once you replace the train of
thought to your subconscious unconscious
I want to say unconscious but your
subconscious subconscious feelings of
they're judging me yeah oh god if I
don't make this like awkward hmm I
usually go when I get a word and that
that outward is like of course I lost
the thought you just completely changed
your train of thought to maybe finding
this other like what you were speaking
about to this topic of like don't judge
me because I can't think of what I'm
saying because I'm not perfect
yeah so the second that we think that we
don't know who we are and we think that
the the second that we allow our
thoughts to convince us we know the
other person's thoughts yes we lose our
own thoughts so we give away our own
thoughts just by letting them go yeah
well it's part of like what we learned
we learn like if you make a mistake you
must immediately correct it there is no
sitting on your mistakes and figuring
them out it's immediately you need to be
correcting us because that's how you
reprimanded a kid touches the stove and
you say like no yeah there's fear
immediately because you just got yelled
yeah and it was seemed angry and now
you're sure you're conveying these angry
emotions right and so now I need to make
sure that I change that mistake that's
instinctual but it's also like yeah
we were we grew up with those like fix
that don't do that yeah rather than like
we grew up like with them constantly
acting on their instincts right not and
because I said so
yeah so that's something that uh but my
sister says out says a lot because I
said so and so I've been trying in in my
search so in my search to understand
like my own mind I realized that a lot
of people are like this but me
especially I have to have my end goal I
have to know my why or the order of
things that I do in the middle gets
really [__] messy and organ
unorganized yeah stressful so like if I
don't know why I'm doing things so if
someone tells me I was in a difficult
difficult kid growing up but I've always
been different I didn't understand
things because when someone says because
I said so I say that means nothing but
yeah that makes no sense so how can I
possibly follow that or do exactly what
you want me to do because you said so
like who are you who gave you like what
are you yeah like so I have to know the
the the why I think it I personally I
think it was a respect thing for a
really long time because again in
religion most religions and just most of
society you respect your elders and
that's that's a cultural thing by
decades I'm sure hundreds of decades
it's a you know you have to be have that
respect and I think that our our parents
especially grew up respecting their
parents who really respected their
parents a lot of that that age group is
that way and so I think that we were
thinking less now if you if you go into
a school and I you know an example would
be me as a sub saying to the kids
because I said so mm-hmm and they're
they're in a world now where they can
say well who are you to say so right so
they're longer about respect yeah the
ground of that like the ground of
communicating what needs to be
communicated to our younger people is
now shaky right because that's taken
from us like the trust so an old person
can't like it in a small community let's
say 150 people if an elderly person
comes up to you and you're five years
old and he says hey like there's there's
a storm coming we need to go inside
here's this is the most important thing
in your life right now tell your parent
tell her
sister tell your mom to go inside
there's the storm you say okay of course
you're not the person to much do ya but
now anybody is allowed to do anything in
like we have a weird like communism it's
not about but we have this weird new
thing in it anybody has a voice yeah
we're all pretend leaders in we're in a
westernized culture has adapted to it's
turned on itself
yeah it's a little bit dangerous
everyone's a leader you know in it
there's always been that don't be a
leader right or don't fall and I was
like yeah I'll be there [__] that there
how many times in this like growing up
can you remember seeing a sign that said
don't be a follower be a leader what
lead or whatever so there yes sir but
what if followers heard that and they
think that they're leaders right see
that's the thing
yeah people you're not leaders and this
is my last podcast cuz I don't think I'm
really a later I'm just trying to wear a
mask and follow my intuition but here we
go I actually wrote something this my
plugins again this is an excerpt from
just like my stockpile of writing like I
don't know articles or something but
it's not the full thing it's just like
an add-on to things of this same it's
it's about talking about like society
and ego and stuff and the ability to see
things outside of ourselves is where all
of our understanding and what it means
to be human lives
the overexpression of the ego in our
culture is crumbling many of the pillars
that most Americans still cling to the
Internet has hijacked the human brain
and been used as an accidental weapon
causes targeted at information based
avatar sides of our actual selves have
gripped us in tribalistic communities
have found ways through the connections
of the internet to reach out into the
real world a man with a microphone can
arms and wings of evil to fulfill his
plan a man with a story can reach the
weak-hearted
the broken the unknowingly broken they
easily misguided the children the adults
the Senators the good people the bad a
man with something to say can change the
course of history what a power to
withhold no one man should have all that
power a great storyteller once said it
is the second commandment of being human
knowing your duties to be truthful
knowing your power to take the first
linguistic commandment of what we have
all decided together means everything
and use it wisely to not lie to not
stand on any Rock and declare it as more
yours than it is everyone else's we are
of this earth we share this earth this
thing here is equally ours we are fools
to not attempt a coinciding way of life
together that benefits the ground that
pushed back up at us the leader in the
follower are a yin and a yang of our
society the ability to have an instant
megaphone has begun to dissolve both the
heart of the man on stage or at all rock
and it's yang the audience the pride
below the ability to reach through
nobility sorry the ability through to
the ability though to other pieces of
the world is a godly power the ability
to reach through to other pieces of the
world as a godly power to connect the
world is perhaps one of the most
beautiful things that I could dream of
being a part of in my generation the
skyrocket of information and knowledge
that can now be instantly shared is not
merely extra Sun and extra watering to a
plant but suddenly the ability for a
plant to suddenly transport itself
across the entire world physically while
deep in its original roots with each
noble connection a smaller large seed of
beauty is planted or sprouted with each
reincarnation of uncle Scar that stands
upon Pride Rock also the yang of
beauties Yin Singh seed is planted how
dare you claim to be Mufasa when you are
merely a plant a great storyteller knows
growth and observation a great
storyteller practices in private what he
preaches in megaphones or open air the
ability to have any following makes you
a storyteller the great awakening of the
internet culture is a step back to
realize realize we have accidentally
created an ego avatar world of weeds and
dishonest stories to water and
strengthen our untrue truths and have
one more paragraph through stories
around campfires and men standing on
tall rock we created a follow a leader
commands any follower who doesn't feel
they had the strength to go of it alone
to fight back and find a way to live in
some form of best way a leaders role
whether the following be to one single
little brother or to millions of people
the language and agreement we have
agreed upon is that a leader does not
take his role lightly a man who stands
on a rock
a man who leans in to express this story
around a campfire and be so truthful you
can feel the emotion being given a great
storyteller is a leader a great man who
stands on the tall rock before anyone
who may follow has a job you with a
voice of any amount of take over
follower following you you were the
voice of any amount of takeover
following have a duty and a role an
absolute destiny to stand on that rock
and truth how dare you take the lives of
these people in bait how dare any of us
interject what we know more than them
into the spots where intuition is now
caged in them the role of any leader or
any person taking any others amount of
time seems very apparent but you as a
leader upon this rock still stand nobly
you are the symbols of our world for
more perspectively high up rocks I'd nod
to you and quickly get back to sorting
myself out the butterfly must let go of
the caterpillar to be a butterfly you
need to learn your cocoon not your
butterfly like there's tandon's then you
just have to kind of like dude yeah but
for me lately it's been great trusting
it because I've been able to like oh
this actually goes with this chapter I
wrote four weeks ago yeah like like this
I've been writing accidentally about
this how to be a great storyteller like
somehow this is like some sort of
in-depth chapter or maybe eventual book
that I'm writing weird that's cool yeah
but anyway so yeah so everybody having a
platform
everybody having platforming strange
yeah yes also you led into a little bit
of the conversation that I think we
should say way into a little bit mmm
is the silent right touch the mouth
price I'm bummed like normally I'd be
thinking about I think about it it's
okay okay I'd be bummed it makes me not
feel so Jeremy anymore around meetings
yeah see it's like I don't even try to
do that absolutely just in my head well
actually it's still prominent but you
don't act on it the way that you used to
mm-hmm
I can see it I'm like oh that's not
actually that's not who I want to be
because you you can choose who you want
to be what we're talking about ladies
Jones we just cheered our beers here
Deschutes fresh-squeezed IPA it's one of
favorites please and we cheers in my
mouth part touched her mouth part and
usually I'm not really I don't like
women my mouth fart touch her mouth fart
her mouth fart FA RT touched my mouth fa
RT no but we just know normally I don't
like to touch people are going out
people and I in so that's what we were
just talking about anyway so we're what
we were thinking we would segue into the
difference between we've we've had this
Jake and I really sat down have this
conversation multiple times before you
and I take a yeah I mean few people know
are gonna know or wait what are you
asking yeah yeah you can say Jake and I
I mean it seems like I've been going by
Jacob more now but that just seems like
a weird Star Wars thing I made up in my
head oh yeah oh yeah actually no it's
your world bring your world into mine
yeah oh yeah tell me wait Jacob now
we're discussing earlier and quite a bit
lately actually the difference between
our generation here we are
age 27 both of us 27 and we're kind of
discussing a little bit about when we
were young or when when we grew up we
grew up without technology and then as
we've gotten older we've been able to
learn it and use it utilize it without
being really
frustrated by it so there's our parents
age they're a little bit older they have
only seen the world from relatively most
of their life was lived without
technology and then they they had to
kind of grow into it and they're still
kind of learning then you take the the
youth who have you know anybody under
the age of like honestly twenty even a
little bit older maybe twenty three and
yeah really it wasn't much long or much
longer you know we started I think I
started maybe like third grade learning
how to use a computer and that that
still seemed pretty like yeah we just
had tired it it was only fun for us
right like it was it was crazy like it
was never like I don't even remember
typing like of course it was a class you
have to basically Coheed school me and
like gonna link typing but like there is
still like this is amazing that we're
like learning how to use this you
learning to use a computer
yeah well but our our old generation
only have positive times because we just
got introduced new [__] like every
[__] month there's just new stuff and
we just got to enjoy the new stuff and
then drop it and pick up new stuff and
drop it yeah and so and so we I feel
like we rode the the the technology like
let's say like even before yeah so once
the Mac came out once the Apple Mac
computer came out like we just got to
ride the openness of it yeah like we got
growing and more and doing more like it
was it was a we learned at the same I
mean not the same rate but we did it as
technology yeah we like crazy and we got
to grow in it yeah well and that's the
thing with technology in the internet
they created their own pathway through
society instead of like hey I have this
thing that I want to present to the
world yeah I normally you go to this is
a dumb sentence but you go to the
president the United States and say hey
can you give this out to everybody
United States and he would say yep and
then he gives it out to every United
States like that's how we think the u.s.
works yeah like we literally do like
like the president says okay well yep
let's put that in the science books this
is true we discovered this so we're
gonna make sure that people know this
like and just distribute it but the
internet cuts through that [__] and now
we get to learn it like directly like on
our own so we learned that we learned a
vastly different way than then most
every other generation
we learned how to go to the doctor's
office and sit quietly at the doctor's
office without watching right and iPad
but we also learned like now when we
want to know something yeah we want to
learn something we go immediately to our
our phones because they're gonna tea or
what you know however whatever it is we
have we have the ability to know both so
we can sit in silence with ourselves
yeah hang out there selves and we can
respect others and we can do all these
things however we are also wildly
intelligent in the way that we have been
able to grow and like we I mean I don't
know I guess I'm able to say it 100
times that we've literally grown with
technology so we have as we yeah
humans grew technology kind of like
intertwined with us I mean I mean it
really is like dude I heard them Duncan
Trussell talked about this one time he
said this he was like think about
technology it started with like it was
this building like we would build like
one computer would be a [__] building
you know like and then they're like okay
and then we make it a shed yeah and then
it gets smaller it's it's this being
that now created itself through our
thoughts this is crazy this is not even
what we're talking about but it created
this being threw out like like it's like
oh we could add this with this we can
make a look to it we can make fire
electricity like humans over time like
kind of I think it's not recently just
in the history of being humans versus
billions of years the third spent life
but like create this thing size of a
building and they got smaller because we
got better we got smarter and then your
size was [__] and then it got to the
point was on our desk yeah like oh no it
was even on the ground like on a modem
and this is one of yeah and then it's
[__] a cell phone it's a laptop it's
a cell phone this this being has made
itself smaller and smaller through our
thoughts through our creations through
the science whatever and then now it's
like it's on our wrist it's it's in our
ears it's like so that's what like so
what you're saying is I guess intertwine
with us like you'd be a fool to not see
this as evolution this is like not okay
granted that that were I'm not hijacking
that one yeah I'm aware of what the word
evolution means I want to be clear that
actually just because I think that
people throw whatever their meanings on
words and say it's absolutely so like
I'm gonna talk about the word evolution
Mike McGinn yeah
it's a new kind of evolution the process
of evolving is what you're discussing
yeah you know without the connotation
that evolution has so so what I think
that so rounding back to what you're
saying
I think that we are able like the reason
why like you know who are we like we're
just you know to 27 year olds we were
like have this like introspective
thought like I really think that the
gift that we have for the world is are
after a thought of like hey we've lived
both these lives like it's not like
we're not jaded and biased off of like
we've had cell phones our hands since we
were two years old we we've had both and
now that like me personally anyway like
I was like so sucked into the social
media thing like I would literally I
would spend 16 hours a day I'm like I
would literally always be on it yes so
addicted to it and like now that I'm
able to remember like it wasn't always
like this like and now I'm rediscovering
like things that I would I knew as a kid
or like just how to observe my
surroundings wouldn't be present in the
moment like I'm I found presence again
and the scary thing is is I was so
sucked into the social media that I
didn't realize that I that presence was
taken from me yeah I thought that every
second that I was on my phone was
literally improving my life yes and
maybe even if I thought that to be true
and even if it was technically really
true just it was it was actually just
information and what you really need to
be doing is enjoying your life and so
yeah yeah see that that's the thing is
like these kids are experiencing like
firsthand where they're not taking a
step back like what did I like about
that like maybe I like alright I like
the color purple in that movie like
maybe I like the color purple more maybe
I should paint with the color purple
like they're not following these like
what did I think about that they're just
taking in information they're just
they're just storage maybe or what if
it's I mean I passive you're passive
with these things I am I go from one
thought to the next and by the time when
I'm on you know I'm done off social
media now I'm not lingering on the
thought I was lingering on before I got
there I'm taking all this information in
and I'm not I'm not learning so are you
saying it's wasting your time or but the
distraction don't you think it also has
very very real potential to change your
mood instantly though
like so you you saying you walked away
you say you wasted five minutes on
social media because you're waiting for
an elevator yeah me fellow awkward
because there's people around you and
you don't want talk to because that's
your personality and so you pull out
your phone you waste five minutes and
like yeah that's fine I'll just wait
five minutes Wilson to do is stand there
on the elevator but like before you know
it you're 90 years old in all these five
minutes thirteen times a day add it up
and you're like oh [__] I lived my life
trying to avoid looking the [__] around
also that sound is birds in the chimney
or bad they may coincide I'm not sure
it's a little freaky in their meeting
health real like sometimes all I'll have
like some like revolutionary thought I
think and they'll go off and I'm like
what out like you know and I insert it
and my thought is like that's a sign bro
that's a great thought write that down
and it's it's probably about like
pigeons or something really and they're
just pissed okay we're back and we're
really distracted I don't think so I
think I know so I've been exploring this
like this is the conversation that if
there was a third person who was just
sitting here like who didn't know it's
very well they probably like what do you
guys like you're so weird but like once
you get to know us like these are the
in-depth thought the the conversations
that we have and this is a dorky ass
sentence but these are this is literally
a real conversation in the other
conversations that the social media age
the Internet age led us to honestly this
[__] never happens anymore like we're
mesmerized by this real conversation
like hey let's take these thoughts and
just follow them because it's our right
to like we're mesmerized by it like as
listeners because we haven't experienced
it for years oh it's so wild and you
know what's crazy is how many times do
you say I hate the small talk that's
something that I that's exactly how I
would explain it is like mmm nobody has
real conversations but then I do I the
older I get the more you know I'm closer
to a lot of people who might my closest
core of friends I can have conversations
with perhaps I'm sorry to do really
perhaps we should define because I think
that if I was listening to this one year
ago two years ago I
not offended but I think that I would
say it's not me like of course yeah I
would say like I of course I have real
conversations I things nobody thinks
that they're wrong so what would you
when you say when we have these
conversations what would you say is the
difference that are I don't know I guess
we're right now we're having a common
adult conversations where you can be
civil you may disagree you may agree you
don't it's not like and I'm not hearing
you just preach preach preach and I'm
saying yeah mm-hmm because I just
totally agree with you yeah you're being
yourself and you have your own opinions
right you're not afraid and we're
combining them too and that's the thing
about podcast too is like having like
such great friends too we can take like
your ideas of my own ideas and we can
[__] an ayahuasca plant them like yeah
whatever
no I watched you mr. Rogan you take like
I guess the the ayahuasca plant you take
two different plans it's like the vine
of one and yeah and they intertwine and
that's how you get so it's 5m EOT I
think is what it's called
and it's actually a biome or something
something in our stomach and our liver
enzymes that when you combine these two
plants together it gets through that
liver ensign er activates it and you get
ayahuasca so the plant ayahuasca if you
eat it or whatever it is by itself it
doesn't do anything but it has to be
come out of this plant which in humans
deactivates are activated so can kill
you know it makes you have the most
profound psychedelic experience ever I
told I'm sorry I went on a tangent I
didn't tell you what ayahuasca was yeah
what does it move on its own is it a
[__] like well actually you know I
had this conversation with my uncle last
night about trying different foods and
we were talking about and I'd seen this
on a documentary and it was in Panama on
it so it was when he had brought this up
I was like oh my god I've seen this
right and he was you know I've never
been to Panama obviously but he's
explaining his experience and I'm like
oh my god I saw a documentary on that
nothing he would have said to me had the
situation been flipped but cool enough
that we were able to connect on that
it's this plant thing like they they
take a leaf of a plant and then another
leaf and they make it into like a box
and they put like nuts and and bananas
and like all these different types of
things and then they put it in hot water
they steam it
like a steam pot plant whatever it's
like a porridge it comes out like
porridge so they eat out of this plant
you know and that's where what is it
like the state like it is it sustains
itself like you can like reuse this
thing where you eat the thing I don't
think you either thing I think it's just
what they cook it in oh and I think they
tie it at the top like they fold it up
and then they tie it with like a yarn yo
imagine this conversation like before
the internet are like before like
cultures relieving drove into each other
yeah like where it's like when you had
been washing your [__] clothes in the
river for your whole life and then like
you hear about like some European chick
like no no they had this thing where
they they take plants and they round it
like this and they make detergent or
whatever they soap or whatever yeah well
that's what I was these things are
revolutionary though I know I'm figuring
it out though so any random pops here
that I didn't edit out because I'm
learning it's it's not you it's I am
still very experimental with this
podcast I'm also an audio engineer who
learns very hands-on and what that means
to me is I have to challenge myself so I
literally will purposely shittily set up
stuff or do it completely different or
completely backwards
because I'm trying to figure out what I
like and I'm trying to figure out what
sounds best so so she's hitting it and
it's I know yeah
it'll get better over time I could make
one for sure promise is that like I
don't think I would be perfect but every
podcast will be better than the one
before like in some form like that maybe
that literally means that I moved this
little pot filter over two inches that's
a victory that's there's a little small
things that and that's how you gotta be
patient with that but anyway so you were
you were speaking on
Oh a technology again we're back to that
yeah I was just saying like um because
of my you know my uncle's in his 50s and
I'm the age I am how do I said I went to
Panama and I was explaining this leaf
thing to him he would never been like I
saw a documentary like that once or I
looked this up or oh yeah I've been
researching plants or whatever you know
like he wouldn't probably have ever said
that because he didn't he didn't grow up
where his first instinct is now go to
the Internet
write this out go learn it this way it's
it's well what do I have in my brain
already that my parents taught me that
you know life taught me because we feel
like we need that so do you think do you
think it's because we feel so equal at
every single conversation that we need
to pull our level of understanding of
what we're talking about no matter what
it is I think I can for me personally I
would think I don't know that I've want
to know that so let me go research it
let me you know because then the next
conversation that I go to whereas
something like that comes up oh my god I
have knowledge on this right okay so we
just pull knowledge from different areas
than our yeah in so and so that and then
so a lot of times we take that and then
we get caught in this wet web right here
is where we caught a web you and her
uncle didn't get caught the web you
talked about this it was wonderful but a
web of what most of us get caught in now
is well what I know is different from
what you know what I learned on this
documentary seems to be different than
what you're telling me firsthand and
like the first-hand person even though
they went 20 years ago they may not
realize that it's changed a lot in 20
years as the world has and so there may
they may argue so there's gonna be a web
here and by wet I mean human created
drama let's say so we're gonna create
this web of disagreement that's an age
gap misunderstanding yeah misunderstood
misunderstood oh yeah even the I'm not
saying these are intentional things
we're just saying like the way that
we've accidentally trained our brains to
be with social media but yeah I think
yeah being able to connect with more
people really does mean I couldn't talk
to you about Zimbabwe before I watched a
documentary on Zimbabwe so this person
on their couch now knows a decent amount
of things of this person who went there
actually knows but there they are
different they can't be like first-hand
experience really is different like we
have to learn nice of you so I'm sort of
like defining why I wouldn't be first
and experience is always better because
I've travelled a decent amount and I
feel like I still couldn't tell you a
whole lot about Paris France mm-hmm I
could tell you what I did while I was
there one little insignificant human in
this huge giant City with all this
history I could tell you the little bit
that I
no from my experience there about some
things but I'm somebody else might have
like watched a 12-minute documentary and
learn more facts and information yeah
and so that's like like who can we say
is right and wrong that's the thing is
we get so caught up on like well who's
right then like what is in Bob way
really I can't and it's like perspective
did you we forget we forget that we're
[__] different in like there doesn't
have to be a right and a wrong in every
situation and that likes that sentence
like crumbles the way people think yeah
but it I'm telling you like it has to
like it's okay like it is okay yeah like
you can be completely a different person
yeah yeah they were installed in you as
robots this podcast is about robots
Microsoft down with Microsoft I want to
be cocky and say that I know of it I
honestly don't
I know it's Apple stuff yeah I don't
know I'm thinking of like kind of like I
I can think of like Windows 98 I think
was the first thing that I had on my
computer before 98 that's when we
finally were able to afford a computer I
think my dad was like fairly nerdy when
we were younger I remember we had like
before a lot of other people had games
and we had like computer games I would
play like a need for speed with little
toggles I love like remembering these
memories that I thought that I lost no
no it was like need for like on the
computer like like a racing game we're
like I don't know I don't know it
doesn't really matter yeah Frogger did
you play Frogger like on like I know it
seems like a pinball would you play
Frogger what's your primary Frogger like
it was like a game console or an arcade
with a computer oh the computer on the
computer
Mima that's crazy we grew up like you
know within 10 miles of each other a
whole life yeah or you know 20 miles and
I've never played Frogger on the
computer I don't think really well we
never had we had a an old school
Nintendo and then I think we were able
to get it like Nintendo 64 we I mean we
were like oh yeah brother we didn't we
didn't have a lot of gaming stuff we
really didn't have a whole lot of stuff
we had we had like the basic necessities
and we ate we I mean oh [__] I had a
cool child at though cuz I was outside
right yeah so okay so explain so where
we're at we're getting so comfortably
sidetracked I just want to keep it like
I don't really need essence people find
essence in everybody so where we're at
now is Castle Rock and that's where I
live now so Jessica and I met after high
school yeah but we grew up within like
kind of like for lack of a better word I
didn't play sports but like it let's say
rival schools like all the all the high
schools in the area are bright yeah
that's what we just it's not terrible
it's fun but I'm it's not no yeah we
don't hate each other we don't burn each
other's stake but but so now I live up
here like I live like within a half a
mile of her where she went to where she
grew up and went to high school in this
area it's it's a smaller town like what
so so let's go and just describe Castle
Rock like like not from our naive high
school perspective which is we were also
talking about like it's a beautiful
thing to really realize like oh like I
belong here too like I am a part of the
community like I I'm here to like I
literally go to the farmers market like
I like I have a yard here I I wave at
people like I am a part of the community
not outside of the community who's just
some Simone who like there's a
gatekeeper telling me what to do so
let's let's from your perspective then
versus now let's talk about Castle Rock
well I mean I well I think I mentioned
this earlier but I I've always really
loved Castle Rock I think it's cute and
I think it's so quaint I've always been
like oh that's home and it's a home that
I've forever been like it was so good to
me Castle Rock was so good to me I grew
up pretty cool honestly I was given a
lot but then I moved thinking like
there's more I know there's more and
I've moved and then now I come back you
know just to kind of like just to hang
out with you and I'm like oh my gosh we
say this every time we walk I'm always
like it's so cute mm-hmm because the
community members have really made it
what it is yeah it's a very it's a nice
little town and and forever it's been oh
I mean it was such a classic it was
classic too you know like the all of the
coaches were pretty much either dads or
like long-standing teachers of course
you probably knew who they were and who
their kids were kids were and you knew
everyone in your class like you know
sometimes Tyler will say like he didn't
know I think I went to high school
and I'm like I knew every single person
and if there was a new person I was like
oh I don't know that person yeah see so
cuz you live what was your graduating
class I think like 120
okay so ours I would say Cal so it's
probably the biggest of the you know
four five schools in the area within a
20-mile radius
you know the high schools I graduate my
graduating class 2010 in Kelso
Washington was 500 or so yeah it was
pretty dang big like it was in a you
know I think I'll double-check that
because but but it was definitely a lot
over at easily yeah yeah but it's it's
so funny to think like so you literally
had an entirely right next to me like
right up here like literally we would
think of each other as rivals in a weird
joking way like we wouldn't realize you
know we would live our like our
interaction wouldn't be like hey we know
we're playing this rivalry game but like
it's pretty great to meet you later in
life like no literally we would say like
that [__] we're in the color that's
not my school yeah
so it's very it's very fun you know in
to really let yourself play on that like
like it was kind of silly the way that I
thought of things like this versus back
then because I grew up with this thought
that everyone here knew everyone and
everyone either worked at the mill or
whatever and then you and Shay Lee and
Megan who moved here and I was like yeah
yeah collaboration yeah of my friends
who I met collaboration I love that way
it's usually collaboration with like
your friends moving to your hometown is
so no because it really is real because
that you're part of me that you guys
like knit look you guys know me now but
like when you guys first moved here I
was like oh my god they're gonna
understand like some of where I came
from and you do you go you know you know
you the people that are at the gas
stations
all right the grocery store you know
they are you see yeah dude you know it's
so funny though is is as when you live
in the same small town everybody else
starts to grow too so the people live in
the gas station right here like right
next to my house one of the ladies cut
my hair like the whole time I was
growing up yeah I can tell so and then
the other lady the whole time I worked
at the mall like since I was 16 years
old she worked at cool scoops or
whatever it was like she worked at one
of the stores in the mall the whole
then I worked there too and so like we
have all three like moved from our lives
and it's funny that seems like such a
simple like well duh doo doo people move
all around all the time but when you
really can take an outro perspective and
look at like oh wow it really is cool to
see that you know I I kind of bagged on
this place when I was younger just based
off of my own childish tendencies of
here's who I am versus who they're yeah
well in in me too Castle Rock was very
uh I mean use the word redneck yeah and
so that was actually a lot of people
it's very offensive apparently so yeah
so I actually had a lady on a plane ride
who like explained she wasn't offended
but she did explain to me like you maybe
and maybe a little more careful with
that word which I'm not gonna let people
take away
yeah it was my explaining of it was like
the people with rednecks were working
all day but the banks were there's some
sort of the banks who were creating more
work for them just to give them I'm
talking about you look up the word
redneck but anyway people were but I
think we're also yeah I think we're a
very like long time we probably were
able to be like call me a redneck right
well no and that's how people wear
redneck shirts like they're proud to be
a redneck but like so so me like it's
funny because me like I literally worked
in lumber mill after high school I mean
I there was five years of working lumber
mill like it so me who I thought I was
who I was like no I'm a skateboarder
which literally skateboarders like in my
Celso skateboarders versus rednecks was
like a thing like it was like a cliche
like we literally would fight like we
had to have literally been jumped beat
up by rednecks like literally it was
like a thing that grew up and so it's
cool saying like oh it's not just the
whole town is rednecks like what does
that mean it was just like there was a
couple [__] kids that I threw this
entire town this entire everyone around
them I just assumed and they all sucked
yeah but and it's something that I held
on to without knowing I held on to it's
not like I walked around like literally
just like I would talk to everybody and
whenever but until more recently I was
able to actually see where I'm at in
Castle Rock yeah like oh I'm part of the
community like and I'm not a redneck and
like yeah and redneck is a term
you have in high school when you're just
like subjectively or not able to
subjectively see yourself outside as
much as they the actual yeah I think for
yourself we only thought so much so what
about this age growing up now like
they're like or they're not able to
think for themselves anymore like that's
scary to me like the Internet I wish
this video as it was this radio station
and they were all having a conversation
and when I say I think it's Breakfast
Club yeah yes yeah Charlemagne do I
think yeah yeah yeah out in California
right I want to say yeah I see yeah yeah
they're probably anyway it's not really
really good that doesn't actually matter
but anyway they were having the
discussion about and and this was like
well when you sent me that I was
substituting like nearly every day of
the week so I was with middle school
students nearly every day all on their
phone addicted their phone only talking
about things on social media their every
like conversation that they had had some
kind of like social media innuendo or
mmm-hmm fries or something I mean I was
like seeing it almost disbelieving like
wow these people are really living this
way but in that conversation that they
were having they were saying kids do not
get the like time to them good move it
move it a little bit lower it's at my
hands okay why can't see your mouth
either no no that's fine that's totally
fine like if it takes up a little bit
that's right keep going okay see your
social teacher so no I I'm thinking they
don't get time to themselves cuz when
they're at home and they say I'm gonna
go be alone in my room they are alone
physically but they're on their phones
they're on their iPads there is zero
time for them to write yeah literally
when we were young we actually had that
time you do you have to go to your room
you can't even if you're playing with
your toys you're still like you're using
your imagination you're creating a world
from your whatever we make whatever you
call soul or your inner God or your
intuition like whatever that is that is
shut down when you're with someone at
all times
like even codependent people
well that's what I'm thinking we're
creating that's the trouble we're
creating that bye you're busy here so
you're not thinking you're not thinking
for yourself
you are literally busy on your phone
thinking wow I see that
christina has posted this and I see that
joseline posted this oh my gosh look at
this boy that's so cute because he
whatever 450 likes but they're not
they're not going home at the end of the
day and sitting down saying I like to do
this I don't create this they're going
home and do you know I mean ya know
exactly like lack of well in there
people are gonna see it as a bad thing
they're gonna say like of course okay
like yeah sure that's what I do like
whatever like it's because I have this
in blah blah I'm they're gonna justify
so whatever people may be saying after
the sentence is a justification of
getting our dopamine fix like like
getting our getting our little red dot
like that I mean like all the science on
this stuff is like the science is
apparent like you've we've all heard it
we all know like social media is bad for
us like all that stuff like like but
it's it's changing who we are and it's
like as someone our age we were able to
see again both and now we have this like
me anyway and of course you we have this
introspective thing of okay [__] we're
now in this third stage of our lives
like these up these kids now had one
stage of life and they're still in it
and we actually are on our third now we
had our childhood before technology and
we knew what life was like yeah we had
the present moment like we even had like
I had a very traumatic childhood but I
still knew like I had life and I liked
myself and I was very fun guy like yeah
like I I felt as if I knew who I was and
what I liked and whatever exactly like
they weren't inserted I was able to hang
out with myself and I was I prided
myself on hanging out myself like I
actually have always loved solitude but
so then the internet came around and
like it started out as fun games and
it's real fun and then we get older and
then it's like I said it yeah and
there's our whole life's and then so we
live this life of before technology and
then we live this life of we didn't
really take a step back until right now
but I was on that thing like four hours
a day addiction so here's the thing what
I want to get at is that
the addiction that we have to our phones
due to all this [__] that we can't seem
to quit is not our fault it doesn't have
to be anybody's fault
we're not looking for like the
government is against just like this is
something that this is actually at a
very incredible time like this is this
is something that this is the seriously
and evolution the Internet is this is up
here with the Industrial like this is a
industrial revolution of sorts yeah but
it's it's something new like it's not
even it's not need this one category
it's not like it's like here's how these
answers fit on the constitution you know
the United States it's like no this is
something else we need rules somewhere
else for this so from our third let's
say we're in our third stage of life now
and were able to say like oh [__] you
kids are stuck in where we were at in
our second but since when we when we
were at our first we know what it should
be like what it was like we know what
beauty was when we're at our first stage
of life or technology yeah
fun yeah in creating being alone in in
creating from your brain your gut your
intuition following your gut knowing
like what really makes you happy not
what you think is going to make you
happy because these rules are other
people said it's gonna be copy like so I
think I guess just to summarize what I'm
trying to say is is it feels like people
like you and me like people who are out
to to save the [__] world or whatever
we can I guess yeah it feels like our
duty to point out in any way we can not
to hurt these kids feelings or tell them
that they're wrong but say like hey
we're realizing I'm so sorry it's so
late but like we're realizing like what
you guys are doing with your phones and
what we accidentally said was okay
it's [__] you up it's like I'm so
sorry yeah I know a ton yeah I I'm not
okay so I'm telling if that's a naive
thing like I I research this [__] so
much constantly but one thing I wanted
to make sure that I do on my podcast is
not just blurt out random facts because
it's like oh and I know that this many
percentage of this money because like
there's so much subjectivity about that
and that is not how actual things are
solved all I know is my intuitive like I
I think in depth about my own thought
for very long times during the day like
I'm giving my opinion open to discussion
I'm not gonna say here and argue with
anybody but like I I want this is I come
up with a lot of ideals and then I don't
or or that I have a good decent
understanding yeah and so that's the
thing though and if there's an open
discussion for like heck yeah but like
it is not worth arguing we're not saying
we're right or wrong we're saying like
hey like here's what I think and it
seems pretty real like what do you think
about that like let's not say like well
what if the scientist said because this
is something different
yes it's not this is this is so we're
evolutionary changing and when we think
of evolution we think of growing [__]
tails and then we used to be able to
hunch back and now we can walk like we
think of evolution from the monkey
picture dude like evolution is happening
in our brain is like we're not following
our intuitions of who we think we are
any longer we're doing literally like
escapades of like images of who we like
this seems like what I should like right
and we follow that and that's what we're
saying like our age people it seems like
our duty of sorts to help the young
people be like hey where you going
through now sucks did this anxiety these
all these things that you're feeling
because these things that you they're
real they're real and I felt them
because I try to kill not try to kill
myself but like was very close yeah like
like I want to be so honest with people
just not not just to be like oh I'm an
honest guy like and that you're gonna
listen because I'm just so hard-hitting
honest but like it's like no this is
just a literally normal conversation
yeah this is conversation not that you
should be talking about these things
yes yeah and I'm telling you and if you
just open up the conversation with you
and your friends to talk about these
things
you'll be surprised like I don't wanna
say should be so I should just say but
spending time with yourself and
conversating real conversation so okay
what is a real conversation so let's say
let's make a list of things that will in
this conversation what is not a real
conversation what does something that
doesn't really benefit you much and how
do you ever have a conversation that
does benefit you what's the line
if you say here's here's where it starts
okay
how are you good good that is not a
conversation okay okay but we need we
need to room for small talk though like
small talk is is very different we
haven't figured out how the [__] okay
wait maybe wait hold on hold on maybe we
don't need to room for small talk maybe
we're still trying to accommodate a
system that's [__] up so maybe maybe
when you come over to my house and I'm
not kidding like like maybe when you
come in my house I'm like hey Jess how
are you
instead of saying that I literally like
yeah like I instantly like or maybe
maybe I look you right now I make a
point to look you right in the eyes and
I give you a hug let's say I love you
for four seconds like like it so maybe I
do that you've been tense steering no
I'm okay no no I know I know it's how
the tense but like really think about
like so like when my bro's come over
here like like it's this authentic like
you can see it like if I look back in
these videos you can see like oh like
that's gonna cool like I heard my buddy
like very like I was very in that moment
like yeah I do love him very much
honestly actually men do that yeah often
without realizing it when they like when
you guys grab hands and you like do this
weird like one-armed hug yeah well I
mean serotonin release it's a yeah
that's a cool thing that most men would
never acknowledge they they have a
feeling involved it's just like that's
my bro it's like bro you're hugging each
other okay like not even girls when they
see each other just like like Shailene I
was like hi do you okay so so they're
like girls are robbing themselves and
then of good ol [__] serotonin mana
or oxytocin maybe the same thing that we
get dopamine when it's like a reward so
we hear a ding and Reiko we get
something now we just heard that the
bell would get it we get a treat so
that's what do the ding is our dopamine
but I believe it's serotonin someone
could double check we have written on
the wall somewhere can't read it but so
sick the serotonin is like literally
when you touch someone so like I've read
a book it was a one that another simon
Sinek book but he was talking about the
handshake like your gut feeling like
trusting your intuition which like
nowadays kids probably have no idea what
that even mean
right um like when you you go to do a
deal a business deal and you're like all
right let's sign the [__] and he says
okay any signs that means a you sure and
sign it and you're like
shake on it and he says no and he's like
no I've got time like let's just go and
sign it you have this gut feeling I'm
shaking so when you shake a hands with
another human you're saying like I trust
you like I know that we're crazy and
like I know that you could murder me at
any time technically like that's not
worth another thing but that's really
the depth of what we're thinking I know
that we have these crazy tendencies you
have crazy thoughts just how I have
crazy thoughts but damn it I trust you
to do what's right I trust you to do
what this paper says and so when you
don't have this so touching another
human releases I think it's serotonin or
oxytocin maybe in it it's an actual
thing like even a fist bump when you
touch someone so I kind of wonder all
these little bit long-term effects that
we're not gonna look at maybe scientists
aren't looking at it for another 10
years but like after social media what
our world looks like
so girls because you guys are so not you
this sells terrible girls not touching
each other as much as guys yeah this
sounds terrible no no guys hug each
other and girls as being awkward is what
I'm saying like you girls are now like
you and Shaylee just missed out on
something that me and Tyler get yeah
what does that mean all my friends so I
don't know if it's maybe just dependent
on because I can read Chile's not a very
like technically person person
appreciate yeah well actually Tyler and
I aren't super touchy-feely either but
that's like my best friend see but
that's weird because I think that the
Tyler is really touchy-feely but maybe
that's just like because I'm a female
you know I mean he like really it's an
endearing thing for me but you notice
every time he touches you yeah of course
because I'm well so so that's something
that like that yeah I'm just pointing
yeah I guess this is really a chemical
that is released and everybody's like we
forget that why we do things and the
things that we think are actually
chemicals yeah so when you touch someone
else it is releasing a chemical in your
body and we'd like it we have addiction
stores it and we have like why the [__]
would we you not do what we want to like
yeah but that I mean that's how it is
you know like if I go see my family
yesterday for for example I gave out 25
hugs as soon as I walked to the door
because I was just like elated to see
them and then I also was can
to them and and same thing when I leave
but I do overtime you know my
girlfriend's that I lived with in
Arizona we I don't even remember if we
used to hug you're not but we hug all
the time now we're always you know the
more comfortable our friend group has
all of us have really rippled that
outward I think yeah we are we are very
very hugging friend group yeah it seems
like I grew up with that that very like
comforting and so I think for me I've
carried that on and like a cool because
I love when people I do library well you
know yeah but you're letting done I mean
if you really think about it from our
it's it's the opposite of our primitive
being like like another man who could
like again like I'm not that we're
always thinking fight or flight but like
Tyler could [__] murder me yeah like
I'm opening my heart to his heart when
we hug each other and like he could
instantly stab me like the typical movie
scene we've seen of just stabbing in the
side there so letting down fighting that
like primitive like but so yeah exactly
like it's something so so anyway life
protip real quick is to hug your bros
and hug your girls girls do you need a
hug go get one right now 1-800 hugs I
don't know we get pulled from YouTube
for funding a good site on porn or
something um so let's just link back to
yeah I think it's pretty important to
emphasize the the difference that social
media like and we're not we're not
attacking social media we're not
attacking but you use a social media
we're both have all I view social media
a lot like we didn't I didn't personally
right yeah but you've narrowed it down
was there a while where you had 130
people 29 and I remember thinking yeah
and not to say that those people but do
I want to be your friend every damn day
well no I mean here's the thing though
is we forget our capabilities like we
don't want to admit when we're wrong in
this stems from that process it stems to
we don't want to admit that we can't
[__] handle that much information all
day like we only have let's say we only
have a hundred slots from memory good
stuff in our day 24 hours you've got a
hundred slots for memory good stuff I'm
Dean a lot yeah I'm gonna copyright
memory good stuff that's a lot and and
that you wake up and you get on your
phone and all of a sudden you got six of
those [__] memory spots taken
up because you laid on the phone for
half yeah and so those things when you
wake up they whether you like them or
not like whether it's whether this is on
reddit whether this is on YouTube
whether this is on social media like
even if these are good good apps texting
is sport emailing yeah dude it it you
insert in your whole day whatever you
woke up exactly yeah you're exactly
right and so really and this isn't just
like some fancy thing this is really you
can simplify your day like this this is
like okay so then you wake up and you go
and you get coffee and you take a pee
and that's one more slot okay and I got
seven slots filled up and then you I
gotta poop so you go to the bathroom
after you just peed and hit any poop and
as you're pooping you're on social media
again or you're now checking your other
apps or now your whatever and so well
that's eight and then before you even
leave your house you have 8 out of 100
things taken up and also those things
probably before you even get in the
shower oh god yeah shower I do yoga or
shower I don't yeah I've always been a
morning shower but I've been lately I've
been because I want to push it against
my edges I've been like I'll go a whole
day without showering it's crazy for you
but yeah so I think but anyway so so
waking up around social media or around
other outside influences to where you're
not alone this is I guess like the
importance of being alone and being able
to think through your thoughts like like
is taken away like you only have so many
out of your 100 thought slots thoughts
what thoughts have you hundred thoughts
lots you have like a lot of them are
supposed to be for you like there's
there's something like the days that I
feel my best mentally mental health wise
are honestly like where 90% of those
thoughts were me and the other 5% are
like like had a good common with my mom
who's living with us for a little bit or
than the other 5% is like
one percent hanging on the cat because I
made sure to make time with this cat
that I'd I don't like but I want to like
it and then chaley you know I only get
her four percent I guess but no like
like you got to realize your day I was
just think about yesterday I was hanging
out and I we just had fun it was like I
mean my I mean most of the time it's by
myself I guess I cuz this is my my work
from home process is I wake up and I'll
have casual conversations the morning if
my mom or Shaylee awake but most I'm
there and if they are yeah I put
headphones in and I go outside and I
meditate within 20 minutes of being
awake yeah and so for the rest of the
day they don't really I don't really
talk to them because I'm just they know
that I'm in like a place yeah there's a
little bit it's like going to work yeah
I mean that's that's what it is so okay
so and that's another thing too like the
the new new world this sounds like a
loom daughter's a lad and go see it is
good there's different jobs like mine
like old people older people let's say
let's say even are in our town like
older people who have worked at a mill
their whole life whatever they they are
living in different life now than the
kids who when they are their age it's
gonna be differently that these kids
growing up who are now and who we're
talking about would say under the age of
20 or whatever 27 whatever they're gonna
have a different work life like me I
literally smoke weed during the day yeah
I I'm at home I can eat whenever I want
yeah my job is a creator like in so as
long as I get my deadlines done might
get my things done and then you know
once a month I fly to a different
whatever yeah as long as I show out
there it doesn't matter what I do the
other three weeks I'm never micromanaged
and so like this is an entire world
that's gonna grow up only being their
own bosses right I'm telling you when
you are so reliant on other people all
these dreams that you want to do and all
these all these kids that are like they
want to be this and they want to be that
and all these things like these things
require if you want to be successful at
them they require either working with
other people in a very well way in which
case you need to be mentally intelligent
or mentally emotionally intelligent yeah
Medlen you need to be smart just to work
without people mentally emotionally
intelligent yeah and I truly think from
a man who has lived like like my life is
so exponentially better just in the last
year there's every my 26 years of life
like and it seems like it's it's because
I'm I'm able to really retreat with
myself and sort myself out and I think
to yourself to wait right yeah well and
that's the thing is as much as I would
say I thought that I was doing that you
don't know what you [__] think unless
you you get alone you just talk to
yourself like in me I'm a very in-depth
intricate like thinker anyway I've
always been like that when I was younger
that's what I said
social media kind of sucked me into this
like out here I'm not yeah
Who I am like yeah let other people
control control my thoughts like let
other people influence my thoughts I
guess and think that that's who I am but
like seeing controlling but yeah we're
not doing it on purpose
yeah we're just living our lives like
thinking that we're doing right here I
maybe maybe this is different than a lot
of people I don't really know I because
I'm someone who like I don't like makeup
I'm not super into makeup and I'm not
super into fashion and I'm not super
into like super girly stuff so a lot of
the time what I put on Instagram is like
oh I felt good today about my right or I
really loved this part of my day it was
never like it was it was more inward
like oh I love this own share this at
people versus like I want people to
share love with me about how I looked in
this photo like obviously I liked it
have to to let all of you see it right
which means I loved it I loved it first
and then now you guys you know if you
guys like it that's cool huh but I do
feel like a lot of the time social media
was like telling me in my mind you
should learn better makeup
you should learn cuter in fashion you
should learn how to take better pictures
and not nobody was you know again nobody
was telling just like they're wearing
the mask out you know but you felt you
had to write I felt not even that I had
to just like if I wanted to make it
you know if I wanted to be better on
social media it was almost be for me
becoming like a I was kind of dulling
myself and my skills to adapt to what
everyone else would like on Instagram
exactly but it's crazy because I still
was posting the things that I loved I
loved I love myself I love my dogs I
love ya Tiffany's and my friends but I
was moving these like the way I would
normally edit right you would spend a
lot more time you would over thank them
like in the it's not like you were just
like completely lying like that there
was like like I was never completely
lying it's like I would showcase like
like I would paint a jacket in like I
would showcase that like I generally
like I did paint this like I like doing
I didn't paint this for attention but
the amount of time that I took to like
take a good photo of it and edit it and
like [__] oh my god anything I think of
a caption like yeah and I wonder about
that too oh yeah because you know like
even God I think back to this is such a
funny like back in middle school when I
first met Brittany Jennings right and
she had like when myspace was just
coming out she had the coolest [__]
myspace and oh she knows so much about
this her myspace like everyone was like
she knew how to do the underscores in
the cross out song I feel like I knew
that Brittany had a dope ass like dude I
feel like her glitter graphics were off
the charts I think she and she took the
camera angles her up here like she was
the person to unlock that I think she
was like the epitome of like you don't
know about social media I know about
[__] social media right a very young
age so I remember thinking like yeah but
it's things like that were I think
certain people have this knack for like
like I used to want my ice to not care
about my Instagram and then I suddenly
started being like oh I wanted to be
clean all the same color you want as a
whole you want it to look good yeah yeah
so I think that part of you know part of
me like that was that was what I was
addicted to was making it look perfect
and because I'm a pianist yes see that's
what I love doing like I
I enjoy the representation of who I'm I
say I'm saying I am like it's not even
just like here's who I think I am it's
like here's here's like the cover art of
who I think I am like in that I would
always say the highlight reel yeah right
but like the thing about that and that's
that's cool like I think there is a
general a lot of people have a general
understanding
I guess that like I know that you also
wear sweatpants outside of this like I
know that whatever like but we say we
know that we say I know but then we see
them in person and we're like they're
not as how does they wear in social
media yeah like these are real things
like and we we joke this [__] off like
well yeah of course I'm not like I've
been drinking like whatever like yeah
like whatever you would normally say
after that sentence in your friend group
in a group message with your friends
yeah like that's bad like we're
attacking ourselves with comedy in
justifying the weird [__] that we're
doing and like I think we're able to
take a step back and look at that now
and be like oh [__] that's bad don't do
that guys so this is a question I held
on to a lot because I am very witty and
I am very like I'm a smartass and I'm
always gonna have something to say
always and I don't I don't dislike that
I actually really appreciate that about
myself that I'm a talker I used to be
like I talk too much but I never told
myself that I was that what does it even
mean like who says that here's the
amount that you can talk during the day
you're allowed to talk this much around
these many people yeah hey you hit your
69 years show your mouth you've been
done talking to your dogs dude Talon I
talked about this yesterday about how
often you talk to the dogs like you have
he's like he's like yeah we have full
conversations where I don't say anything
for 20 minutes things you're just trying
to figure out what you think you're not
actually trying to so okay so let's get
back to that the essence of how great
that is Jessica is is being able to talk
to herself is how we sort ourselves out
right when you're always taking in
something you're never able to either
organize it or output what you're doing
and so people who are always I want to
emphasize even lyrical music in your
headphones like even
even movies on in the background like
anything that is in putting something
that's not like a neutral like let's say
like a [__] piano or like a fountain
sound like sitting in a room by yourself
with no input can you do that
can i well I mean not yeah of course you
can okay I'm saying like as as third
stages here in life like Kenley's like
stuck in second stage people like and
the thing is is they're gonna say no I
can't I have anxiety yeah so the thing
is so what I've learned more than
anything is when you push up against
things that you need to change or like
you think that like you don't like yeah
you so these are these are two things
like you are experiencing the human
emotion on anxiety right you are not
actually your thoughts though so you're
also giving worth you got to remember
like you're still in your like whatever
you're saying out loud there's still
like an intuitive you that's in yeah
let's talk about that let's I want to
talk about the word anxiety because
things that in depression have been
hijacked by BuzzFeed I think right I
don't know this is where you going no
okay I am thinking about the word
anxiety itself and how we've given we've
given weight to it so maybe this is okay
when I was mental health counseling
before I moved to middle school I had a
lot of like eight-year-old kids it was a
weirdly like it was a weird amount of
like all of these kids were I think I
had like six of them and they were of my
first month on the job and I was like
wow you know the eight-year-olds like I
don't know what to talk to them about oh
my god like what does an eight-year-old
boy honestly that's like my least
favorite age I think because they're
just so annoying if you're eight years
old listening for whatever reason you're
[__] annoying
get it together there's some kids
sitting in a car seat still his mom's
overprotective but she's listening to
our podcast because she does your hair
on the weekends or something like kids
ask too many questions and they want too
much attention they drive me nuts I
think we don't actually want the answers
we just want to ask why yeah also you
just want to be like watch me do this
ballerina turns no you just want
attention
Parker I don't want to watch you okay so
you have six eight year old and we I had
a lot of them that and I don't think
this is just I mean obviously I worked
in a non-profit so we did a lot of state
insurance we did a lot of like
homelessness foster children that type
of thing so there's turmoil in the house
I do not think for any eight-year-old
regardless of the the situation I think
that most eight-year-olds are probably
like having this same feeling because
their parents I can tell you that when I
was sad my dad never said let's talk
about you being sad my dad probably did
more things like and this isn't like a
direct you know this is where we're
pointing out this these are things that
now in this new world this new world we
can talk about because it's the things
we're looking back say hey we could do
this a little bit better everybody not
just you there's no faults being pointed
here at all he would say you know if I
was sad and he didn't know why rather
than exploring it and trying to figure
out again you know this is my business
mindset but here's the challenge here's
what we can you know here's the possible
things that we could do and then also
here's the solution or here's five
solutions right honey whatever you think
you know let's try him out so rather he
would just say do you want a cookie
let's go outside do this let's do
something fun you want to do he would
reward my sadness and he'd you know I
didn't any I don't think it was too much
that I became spoiled because I we
obviously didn't have the means to be
spoiled but I lived a very rich life but
I don't ever remember my dad coming to
me and and vocalizing that word focusing
on Oh on a specific feeling or emotion I
had and then describing it and then
finding a way to get it look cuz how
could he possibly do that he doesn't
know do that with himself right that's
the thing like nothing about against him
it's literally just something they've
never been taught something that we are
forced to think about now yeah but so
anyway I think moral the story is these
eight year olds now who I'm helping I
they're learning the word anxiety right
they're saying because rather than us
figuring out how to identify the emotion
and then then work on it we just say as
an all-encompassing word yeah
angry or mad or anxiety yeah anger and
exactly something you know that I like
that it is anxiety and you're
experiencing deal we do outright say
emotionally I'm feeling a little bit
embarrassed because right how many kids
are feeling embarrassed at that age yeah
good because we we don't look in depth
of like okay so what are you really
feeling because if you just if you sit
down [__] talk to him instead of just
trying to get them away from that
feeling and try to hide that feeling
push it away if you just sit down and
talk to him which granted it's super
hard to do there's a lot going on in our
world but think you'll get it like so
why do you feel like it's why are you
crying alright
where you crying why crying like
whatever they get down yeah but yeah
it's so in your job as a parent or an
adult or whatever anybody who could
influence is say like to point out to
them like there you go you silly goose
like I don't you have to be mad and
they're like oh that's how my emotions
were like okay yeah and they don't want
to feel any more than you want them to
feel it so if you sit down like okay
we'll shoot man let's all right you're
eight years old like okay so what do you
think oh so what Cynthia said made you
mad that seems that probably made me mad
too you know you get down to their level
and you talk to them and you can you
tell them like this is how we work
through our emotions but there's nobody
get down on the level anymore because
there's a very huge disconnection with
the young age or no other people like
and this is a little even like eight
years old versus twenty seven years old
like this is even sixteen years old
versus fifty-seven yeah if you are let's
say younger than thirty you are
disconnected as [__] then like there's a
huge gap yeah it's a twenty-five even
two but also like you're disconnected
but you've also been made fully aware of
mental health and emotions right because
in school you you now in the schools now
especially they're saying like what
color do you identify with if you're red
you're angry how do we fix that they're
working on that they're doing some
social emotional signs which cut I wish
they could have when we were young right
right that's instead you know and and
then there's people who this kid has a
DBE or ADHD whatever we've decided to
diagnose him with but the teacher rather
than saying sit down sit down he asks
buddy can you take him for a walk right
to do that now yeah yeah who wants a
distraction you want something and it's
you know I get it obviously we can't be
taking the kids out 15 times a day
because they're distracted because
nothing
well like Pavlov's Bell you know you
write you teach someone to do it and
they're gonna do it but I think the
essence there is that like like we are
now we've always known we're very
different the way that we learn things
like the way that like an ADHD kid it's
very hard for them to sit next to
we're just saying a general ADHD kid
whatever whatever that means of your
brain sitting next to a kid who is very
like a straight-a student a 4.0 like
it's very good like literally if we were
younger Shaylee sitting next to me like
like I don't [__] learn the same way
that she does and also her life is going
great and my life has an absolute
brushfire at home yeah like in trying to
have these two people say hey get the
exact same focus and get in this clique
get your head in the game right now
we're learning [__] statistics yeah
and and you're also sitting there like
why do we need to learn it cuz I'm
someone who needs to know why I like
that said all right I need to know why
before I even start these trail you're
saying why don't you learn it and
they're saying this is what you learn in
school and I'm like why do we learn in
school what is school and I'm really
like trying to figure out like why we're
doing any of this your Maslow's
hierarchy you're going through like I
don't have security which messes
hierarchy I know I've heard of it what's
the s like your most basic needs are
like food water shelter right holding
maybe as one of you and then once you
those things are okay in your life right
then you can move this to the second
level yeah in the second level I don't
know you know how they go I know the
very basic very basic and then the very
top is like self identity so so you're
moving from this you can't if you're
homeless you cannot go to school and
focus on or if your parents are fighting
yeah it's not an option you can't go to
school and think I'll just set this out
here on this counter when I come into
class and I'll learn visit yeah you
don't have that ability in your person
of the ability right now to teach you
because they're causing this terrible
thing like they don't want to be doing
that holy [__] like of course they don't
want to make a terrible life for
kids but we're accidentally living out
the [__] that our parents put on us so
then you can't you're not able to move
to to learning and then you're not able
to move to this next I wish I could
remember what that all the ones I always
remember the baton the most basic one
because I think social services I've
been in it yes so is it like hierarchy
of needs like like we need like so it
was for example when we walk into a
building we need to trust that whoever
the workers were who built the building
built it these correct ways it's not
going to fall and kill us like we all
need trust even that sense like is it
like that
that I mean I guess you could either
what we need in order for sighted
society to work to live okay so this is
before before society this is just to
survive see yeah so we'll definitely
have to look this up because I'm type
right I'm trying to explain it so like
I'm picturing because it's a triangle so
imagine a triangle go over the food
triangle yeah we don't [__] get me
started on the [__] food trying wild
freak out and a little like columns in
it okay so the bottom column it
basically is a theory that if you're
going to you're going to school this is
a good example so you're you're a eight
year old boy going to school but your
mom and dad dad just went to jail and
you just found your mom dead this is
very drastic he's all over again
you found them dead mom dead dad's gone
so you don't have any security anymore
or any safety feeling because you're two
people you trusted the most
mmm-hmm are no longer in your life and
then you get moved to somewhere that's
not a home you sit in at the Social
Services office for eight hours until
somebody can come take you some this
perspective is all from an
eight-year-old perspective this isn't
adult thinking this is an eight-year-old
trying to understand their life yes okay
so then oh my gosh I'm kind of hungry
you know as an eight-year-old you don't
make food yet yes so you're relying on
your parents who are now nowhere to be
found
cuz your answer how to get food is go to
your parents and you don't know it's not
there your parents said don't don't talk
to strangers so you don't want to talk
to them
social service worker or the cop yeah
you're sitting in here thinking I'm so
hungry oh my gosh I'm so hungry good
since well I don't even remember when
because my dad went to jail last night
when I was so sleeping and I woke up to
this so this 8 year olds thinking all
these things aren't being done for him
so he has no no food and no he has a
shelter but he's still thinking about
yeah he doesn't trust it because all he
he's still in a stranger's place yeah
like what is this building I mean what
is this my strength my mom my dad my
security is gone yeah and so basically
that's like the most primal thing what
do we used to need when we were cavemen
per say we needed food shelter and water
yeah right so we needed the most basic
instincts so if and I use like
homelessness as a good example as well
if you don't have a home and you don't
know where you're staying from night
tonight and you don't know if you're
gonna be cold or hot or if you're gonna
get any food for the next five days you
do not you cannot start working on the
next level of yourself you can't start
working on living and and I say this for
substance abuse that's a huge one so if
you're someone who is an addict and you
don't you are not set up this this is
why this this theory in Holland or
whatever works because they're setting
it up with a home they're setting them
up with food and water they're setting
him up with a job they're literally
setting their government is setting them
up to be functioning like let's give you
this we know that humans need this
lowest level of this low tsunami this is
the absolute this is what humans need to
get themselves to sort it out right if
we can yeah we should totally be able to
give people that right halt in whatever
so they did a thing right so this was
the place where they did like they open
up drug facilities like for drug users
right yeah so which you the products
been that a little better than I mean
those it was it one of the fun ones or
one of the not fun ones yeah but they
allowed these people to come in and it
was I would say it's essentially set up
like a social services or a welfare
office something along those lines where
you come in we can give you a whatever
dose you
and and there that would be we would
have a really hard time with that here
because who's to say your dose is too
high right we'd almost have to start
them out with it always we'd almost have
to give this a packet built on them like
ok we started out with our always 10
milligram or whatever yeah right and I
do think they do that they must because
it's just reckless like you 100 are you
sure he's like yeah bro you have to
think about who's gonna who's gonna
provide that but that came from their
taxes that's something I think that they
had decided anyhow they come in and
these people are allowed a daily dose
and I don't know how many times they
were allowed in or out or whatever but
even if it was one for free this is a
lot you go into like this is literally
like going into the hospital to a floor
they actually you go here so imagine
your dignity like if you're drug user
like you like you're not going to feel
like you're not a piece of society
you're gonna feel like a piece of
[__] scum who has to hide you're not
gonna feel like you need to go into an
alleyway to meet some sketchy dude who
you hate but you have to maintain this
relationship with because he's your
dealer he literally go into this place
and it's white in there's a lady she's
45 and she drives a Mercedes she's
friendly to you CD why
yeah she Stacey's mom you see what's up
with Stacy like hey when I get it
together in five months can I talk with
Stacy can I hang out with her what no
but like you like just the act of that
opening up these clinics yes Mike that
gives people obviously the stability
that they need to like actually start a
ground of life again
yeah but it also it reminds them that
like not everybody [__] hates them
and not everybody sees them is just a
piece of dirt on the side of the road
like also a home in a way it could be
right you're very right that's a good
point yeah it's a baseline if all else
fails you know if all spells in their
life they're going to sleep on the front
porch of that place right or something
yeah so anyways we can handle it there
yeah yeah the essence of these places is
that they give the lethal dose or you
know legal we go I don't know what if
they legalized or not regardless they go
in and then they also were there to help
these people get housing because people
don't know like how do you know okay you
gotta get your [__] together like what
does that mean they don't know how to
get together like also how many times I
mean god I felt an application actually
I've had enough jobs in my lifetime that
I filled out
- mm-hmm easily 27 times let's do the
same but I've had so many jobs I have
filled out so many w-2s and I still to
this day have to ask questions about my
application resume whatever maybe so you
imagine someone who doesn't have my
experience trying to fill out their
first application dude yeah like the
stuff that we're taught in school is not
okay well it may be different now but it
wasn't super relevant it didn't seem
like no you needed to know that canister
last time I made a resume before I
graduated high school yeah was ninth
grade and you know what I was I mean
Britney Jennings I were stealing [__]
cookies we were not in class we're all
talking about kids these days they're
social media and we're just stealing
cookies life got me back but I
definitely am karma kicks in sorry what
what is karma to you I I feel like the
the Instagram Roffe on sale for $7.99
poster and I'm just saying because I
have plenty of those karma yeah like
what what is karma to you like what was
karma mean I wouldn't say like oh that
guy murdered so he got shanked in prison
yeah he will be murdered that's yeah
it's not I for an i for me for me it's
like yo I didn't I did like 15 things
wrong in this same one day and then like
today I accidentally tripped over
something it's like life saying like
hang on
you know think take a minute to to maybe
think about some doing better or it's
like little things that just kind of
give me the indicator of like see how
good this feels when you were a good
person and Karma's not always negative
for me I think karma a lot of the time
is like hey like a reminder how does it
feel right now because you just like did
this nice thing for someone like
sometimes that work no I don't
necessarily want to go wipe down the
tables for you when you could you can do
it yeah but I'm gonna go do it and then
I'm gonna be like I'm glad I did that
yeah because three minutes well so
that's the thing as is right there that
you don't automatic this isn't something
like if you wipe out the tables for your
coworker you receive a magical gift yes
Kharma like no this is something that
you need to be intelligent enough to be
like I know that this person only has
100 slots in their day yeah
instead of making them take one I'm
gonna use one of mine and I'm gonna
clean that [__] table like for you
giving up like girl I got you
I'll go clean that table like get like
that to me is like so good karma it's
like you give yourself or allow yourself
to open up to that feeling of like I
just used one of my hundred slots for
Jennifer over here yeah because I know
cuz I know that Jennifer's happened she
has a hundred [__] kids ohm in her
last rough like like I would do little
things that would be Instant Karma for
me like receiving of karma like I would
feel good like and this is an even ego
based I would feel good about I
literally had a guy that I used to work
with that would fall asleep at work and
like he would never like in ridiculous
ways like he was a hard worker he's a
good guy but I also know that like we
would be s enough to where he would he
has literally four kids or five kids I
think and they were adopting two more or
something like he was literally
dog-tired me fall asleep and it takes me
two seconds to just do a little more
work I was kind of tired it kept me
awake anyway we're like the Karma the
thing about Karma the reason why I asked
you what you think about it is the
secret of karma that people don't
understand is they you you give it to
yourself yeah like you you have to open
up so the good karma you have to open up
to receive it
but bad karma like receives you in ways
that you don't know good karma you get
to choose bad karma you don't get to
choose you choose the bad decisions you
made but the way that reacts later on in
life it makes your thoughts polluted or
whatever yes that's on you and you don't
know how it's gonna be so at least if
you're gonna choose your karma choose
good karma because it feels good you
know exactly what it is like something
necessarily safe and it's not always
predictable but it's like I know that
I'm gonna try the best at least make
this person feel better I think people
use the word blessings also as good
karma and then because karma is almost a
superstition and because blessing is is
identified with with a religion a lot
more people use the word I think that
Karma because I and it doesn't to be
good karma like oh yeah I went to the I
won the lottery or I went to the right
no I got this free thing like good karma
is just yeah I think that I think the
word car
I think that we all have like with our
cultures all just being [__] clash
together with everybody just like
connecting so quickly and so
indefinitely like our language is kind
of being teetered a little bit and it's
a little dangerous yeah like like words
like karma like so we see see words like
let's say even BuzzFeed words like we
see these words and we kind of take the
meaning that we've been given and we
just alright that's what that is yeah
like so we're like if we know literally
the word karma like those kids who they
never wouldn't learn the word karma in
school consciously alias and then they
know what karma means based off of one
Instagram account they follow and that
Instagram account could be like Karma's
a [__] it's gonna get you yeah you
[__] if you ding my car you're gonna
get a car wreck like and people
literally walking around as if like this
is how the world works like and language
is very tricky like we have a lot of
slang how that's what people think karma
is if people think the word ego mean
people think the word ego means like
something equally as up to says that
people think it means like was when
you're really cocky and it's like no
that's I I could write and I think I
don't know if I'm writing it but like
there's a book about ego that I could
write it seems like I'm writing it every
day like trying to explain what the [__]
ego is to people like like the word
start taken from you say maybe maybe
this would be more realistic for us to
do is to give an explanation of what's
happening and then say this is the word
like ass like what are what's the word
that's coming to your mind right now
hmm what does that mean to you like what
the description is that you're giving
right the book that you're writing if
you said you did not say the word ego in
there at all and they have all these
descriptions they might come up with a
hell of a lot different like dictionary
definition what you're writing about not
ego yeah see that's think we only have
one connection when you as soon as you
see the word our brain automatically
connects to the the most commonly known
thought about process right connection
so ego Oh cocky see so I think there's a
huge danger in that we think we know
when we're arguing we're not let's just
say our left versus our right when we're
arguing hardcore as Americans whatever
we think we know what each other means
we don't I think we're [__] talking
different
that languages that sound similar and
we're like so by this you mean this and
you're like what the [__] are you saying
you in it no there's water so it's rain
yeah no it's it's dangerous like it's
it's something like so even think back
to like my example of like using the
word rednecks it's like when I say
rednecks like I now know just by talking
to learning something new that like
there's places in the world where like I
shouldn't say rednecks yeah but like us
around here it's like very normal so
this is the exact same word with
multiple meanings and it's not one of
these complicated like new slashes kne
wi new or night slashes day and night
this [__] is new this is we invented
this [__] on accident guys dude I'm just
saying like the [__] that we
accidentally invented a clash of
languages and we're fighting with in the
clash of languages that doesn't need to
be there I think that that's not a
complete thought I should write that
more but it's funny cuz like I'm like I
wonder like what peer I'm out on yeah I
don't think when I'm following whatever
it's fun that I love that dude that
experience experiments are my favorite I
mean I'm I think back to the new canoe
you know Styles it's funny because it
but again we created language right so
we've created things we we have created
these weird weird weird topples like we
can't think of a new way to put these
letters so we're just gonna take some or
add some yeah I think we're using it as
their baseline like no I mean I mean
like I'm not saying that I'm dude I
don't know what the [__] the answer
would be or like like what it would
possibly mean to create a new language
but really we language is being tricked
upon here because we language the only
reason that Ling would exist and that
it's all a fluent thing is because we
agree that it all means this thing like
it's like when I say turd but you know
exactly what turd but means right but
like what if I was like no it's not snow
what I mean like
if I meant like you're not sitting in a
chair that's a table yeah it's like like
if we had a disagreement on what actual
things that are we say facts mean and
that's what's [__] happening people
are saying that's a [__] table and
you're like that's clearly a chair you
idiot here's why I'm gonna stab your
family like but this is actually a table
because yeah like it's it's so hard to
coincide you know actually I would I
think I would equate this that kind of
covers to the left on the right like the
political side I would equate it to a
bench and a table so you can have a
coffee table
then could also double as a bench right
but one side is like no absolutely no
this is a bench and you sit on it and
you definitely don't put food on it like
that's not how it goes but then somebody
else puts it in front of their their
couch and they're like this is a table
what do you mean this is definitely
table I bought this because somebody
else labeled it take they devote the
rest of their life to arguing about
which is right the tape which one's more
table II yeah is this actually table or
bench I mean is it all of a sudden you
have Facebook groups that are tables vs.
benches right and then you have actual
like riots that started as tables where
as benches but now they're considered
conservatives people cannot even like
the table people even though there's
like 700 million other things they could
like together like hey you know what do
you think this is a bench oh well the
other things that we the other six
hundred nine 9999 things we like about
each other mm-hmm oh those go out the
window yeah we really love funny dude we
have a knack for finding one thing we
disagree with what how does it go more
what have YouTube like ripped my [__]
off like like that's clearly so clearly
the exact song and key this is a
reincarnation
you don't have your the rights to sing
this song you're so good no no it is
really we do we have a knack for finding
one [__] thing that we like
like there could be like really think
about like when someone's like hey this
is so-and-so like oh this is new you're
the new okay here's a good example
you're at your job and you're the senior
person you got a co a new person and
like at least when we were young showing
the new person around you like oh that's
Cyndi like be careful she has five kids
and she's kind of a grumpy [__] like
you love Cyndi you
like you [__] that's your [__] you
know and I've seen it like but like you
accidentally pointed out that one little
thing like it's it's this I think the
thing is is it comes from our primitive
self like hey like always keep your
guard up a little bit because this this
person could stab me in the chest real
quick like and what we need to be doing
is like that's there but we're not going
to vocalize it that literally just
happen to me what are just new place I
got stabbed than Jess yeah damn no I
metaphorically Sanchez yes no I walked
in and this girl was introducing me to
and then the person else is to be
training with actually was late like a
food is late and so I was like oh I
don't know I'm just betraying with
whatever I don't know anybody in and
beforehand when I was like following
this role around getting some stuff
setting up for the day she had mentioned
like oh yeah
you know so-and-so your bartender watch
out for you yeah you have to get used to
her she's kind of a lot first and I'm
like you know when it when so then
preemptively
when this person comes in I'm like
already bracing for like yeah you have
an expectation to an X to an extent
absolutely was distant at first and very
like you didn't purposely do this no I
didn't her you don't [__] train
somebody new handed God so you went into
this place feeling her burden because
that was reminded though thankfully I'm
experienced but that's what I'm saying
one in like 500 people that you train in
your life is actually like competent and
you don't worry she's like go pick up
the table right go wipe the table down
yeah so when you're a trainer you're
someone who has to consistently train
you're like but it's also a very due
dates it's a responsibility it's
something that you like you taking it
lightly means that the rest of the time
this person works in this place they
have handicaps because of you you [__]
like that's the thing like I get it I
totally do because I've trained tons of
people know where she was thinking her
where her personality was coming from
and why this other girl would have said
it however yeah I am thankfully
intelligent enough emotionally
intelligent enough
to be like I will fill this out for
myself because this girl who told me
that seems a little bit I have a very
strong self-confidence especially when I
walk into a place where I'm like I have
done this before so I'm not gonna act
like a little like to do generally I'm
gonna walk in and say all right how can
I help you how can I be on your level
how can we right so because my
personality was a little different than
hers I'm like she does not I am not
intimidated by her like the way yeah
it's because that girl was giving you
her experience based off of where she's
at saying this is an absolute truth it's
like yeah for a person like you yes that
is maybe true true that's that's the one
thing you should point out but that's
maybe true but and don't get me wrong
like I've been in that girl's position
before where I was like certainly
trained I'm like hey this person you
gotta be really touchy with this person
make sure you do exactly this and in a
restaurant it is helpful to know like
this bartender does not want you to pull
the tickets this bartender right see but
though those are a little bit different
those are like okay so but those
conversations we have all these unspoken
words or words that like we can't say
even though we're looking each other and
it's not saying them I can't work like
so these are the kind of conversations
that are being buried more and more and
more with all this social media thank
every thing like all these fickle
conversations are coming through to the
service surface and they're being the
only thing that we talked about so like
right what I heard was right yeah
because really like so say if three
months you and this girl constantly butt
heads and you're like we really don't
same and she thinks like whatever like
whatever situation is like do to solve
that problem it's gonna be uncomfortable
and it's not something we're taught how
to do by our parents of course not
because they don't do it either which is
fine but we need to sit down with them
and say hey we're working together every
day and I value my life and I value your
life I value your time went by in my
time how do we work better together we
don't have to be friends how do we
repair together and you literally if you
can look them in the eye and have that
conversation and they're not gonna be
like well [__] you you're dumb [__]
like as long as you're sitting there
like with honesty and you're not trying
to attack them like you're not making
emotion-based decisions and literally
acting out of sincerity of and even if
you want to be selfish the root of this
conversation is
to make your life better because you're
grumpy when you go home and your
boyfriend's getting kind of sick of you
being a [__] because you just complain
about Tiffany every damn day yeah like
so I think it gets it again looping back
to what we're saying like what can we
what can we tell young kids that are
stuck in the second phase of what we
went through that's their first and only
phase right now how can we help them see
things as like oh I can I could be the
one to initiate this graduation how do
we give them the strength to give
themselves the strength I don't this is
something that I think is very like for
me still I don't have a solution mmm
because I I would love to go you know
one by one into a classroom and take all
of their phones away and all of their
social media away and just have like a
full day of school where they literally
just talk to each other right hang out
but it's like it would take months and
years of that to retract all of the like
eat with all the needs and all the
philosophy the reverses and the fauces
well yeah yeah it's it's yeah humans are
we're very mobile and it's it's actually
unfortunate how am I able where like
it's sad but like these these kids
literally don't know that they could be
better than what they already know you
know what not better but no no actually
better here they could they could do
more than they than they think or that
they don't think actually it's better I
was a [__] turd I sucked like it I'm
not saying like I'm comparing myself to
them like it's drastic because I'm older
but like I was sucked into the social
media thing like literally I had to look
at it every single time I got nervous
anytime I felt an emotion that was not
emotion that I loved I looked under way
or I did something that's a byproduct of
consistently throughout our lives being
told to distract yourself mm-hmm well
that's what all these kids are
experiencing now yeah they're handed an
iPad yeah okay and again when I say all
these kids it sounds like that like it
of course there's not if you can
listener if you can listen to this and
there's somewhere if you let your guard
down sincerely like if there's somewhere
where you can back I kind of do hand my
kids like like if there's somewhere you
can apply any of this stuff sort of to
your life yeah instead of saying well
I'm not that instead of finding the
one thing you disagree with and mean
like well I don't feel that way so I'm
not listening anything Jessica Jake say
like I invite you anything in this
podcast to find the chunks that equate
to you because I want to remind
everybody that we're so different we're
so different like just because you agree
with me doesn't mean you're anything
like me you don't you know many times I
listen up well we talked about this but
in the past you listen to a podcast and
you're like I don't agree with you on
any of that but it's also so good to
hear people's like I genuinely genuinely
if I like disagree with you I'm gonna be
like okay wait explain to me how this
works for you yeah because there must be
a reason why were disagreeing let's
figure out why we're disagreeing why
tell me about your brain because I'm so
intrigued like how'd you learn it that
way because I think of it this way so in
the thing is you're not doing that to
find an answer like an answer as in this
is truth or not true because truth is
the most subjective thing that ever
exists like everything that we know of
truth is based off of somebody if you
just keep following the stream like who
says what truth is like we don't even
agree on a god so what is really true
like but we the parts of what we do we
think make us who we are like everything
that we do we're like no that's us yeah
but if you take an engine engine it's by
itself it doesn't have any car eNOS
there's no car to it and then you add a
muffler to it and there's no cárdenas to
the muffler and the uniting together and
then finally at some point we don't know
we haven't determined you get the wheels
on in the body and then you're like this
is a car yeah in in but when you take
those things apart and you have the
fender in your hand you're like where's
the car eNOS where's the car yeah yeah
yeah we think that we are absolutely
just one thing but we are every single
day you can wake up and you can
literally just choose to be a different
like something like in your like know
who I am is this because I have these
things and I've experienced these things
and here's my story and this is why you
know like regardless like you could this
is the worst analogy but this is just
the extent of it you can murder someone
yesterday and save a life today I'm just
saying like
I'm just saying okay but that is that
not black and white like don't don't
print that on these shirts but I'm just
saying like if you're like I'm not a
good person or I'm a good man or like
whatever like yeah like every single day
when you wake up you can you're you can
create you're not a car you're pieces of
a car and that car is built over time
because yesterday I was this person who
went to work from you know 6:00 a.m.
until 6 p.m. and then I came home and
then I did the dishes and I ate dinner
and I said I don't watch the evening
news and then I went to bed I'm that
person so that's what I'm going to
continue doing because why would I do
anything else like I Know Who I am but
also as you know what you like of course
I like this TV dinner like this TV
channel like that's the thing do you
like it or do your the combination of
your dopamine and here like tell me
about you like but that was a that
really brought me back to like my second
year in my bachelor's degree we there
was a class that I had to take and we
had to watch this video and do it with
him and it was a mindfulness video but
it was literally like eating a Hershey's
kiss
and you know honestly those aren't my
favorite candies but it's chocolate and
if it was sitting in from me I'll eat it
yeah so we have to go through the
process with them and it actually tastes
like butter because chocolate is is I
must be or something derived of
something like you know something to
stick it or want to stick it well like
it's milk chocolate so I guess I should
say that cuz dark chocolate is dark
chocolate milk chocolate obviously has
like cream Basin and our butter and our
salt or sugar I don't even know what the
hell's in it I don't know I'm not a
great Baker clearly I just follow the
directions mm-hmm
anyhow and then you were able to taste
like the the grittiness of it and I was
like well that's weird I've never
thought of a Hershey's kiss so they like
point out these things like think about
the greediness your eyes right okay well
it then then here the wrapper I mean
it's very much so you know you know it's
a Hershey kiss but you're they're kind
of making you point out what are the
things about it that you like the things
you think you love about it so I love
the parts of the car yes yes but in it
this
like a taking yeah I know taking apart
so this is for maybe a belief that's how
I would probably put this is you have a
belief system and this is exactly what
you believe and like the Hershey's kiss
you end up thinking actually doesn't
smell as good as it I thought it did and
then eventually you like honey you know
it actually kind of was buttery and
gritty and it didn't I wasn't as sweet
as I remember it to be you start taking
these these preconceived ideas from what
everyone else has told you and you
slowed down and he's not what do I think
about this item
yeah I think about this outside of what
the commercial tells you that's rich and
creamy right and it has this cute little
jingle and it's like in the you know
it's wearing Christmas trousers one like
you equate it with Christmas which is
also time when you're happy like
whatever and you everybody loves
chocolate it's a slogan that we say in
society like it but it's I think we can
equate that to the parts of the car like
you were saying like some of your parts
of your car don't actually work anymore
and they're a little outdated
yeah so you bought it you know you
bought an 87 fastback yeah
well holy [__] some of the stuff that
that was cool then not actually is cool
to you right now yeah and the only way
that you're going to get the updated car
is if you are willing to let go of you
okay but also I think you don't buy a
car I think that we forget that we
create our own car right like we think
that we bought a car we think that we're
like well my [__] parents gave me this
86 highboy ton Honda I just made up a
tonda hi boy I just made up an up my own
car cuz you can make it but that's the
thing I made up my own car you can
[__] make up your own car no that's
the thing is like we think that we're
handed into this hand-me-down car like
who we are and what we need to be and
the truth is you can just like wake up
even though you murder someone in your
car yesterday wake up I'm keeping that
bring it round you can you can you can
drive you can wake up me like I'm gonna
steal the ambulance today I'm gonna
drive that to work I mean really they're
like you like you could choose me you
want to be every day you could just
choose your Karnas one day but you could
save a life I think you should maybe
don't take Jake's advice
literally okay well if you watch Grey's
Anatomy you know save lives
have your doctor hmm but every doc
today's a great day to save a life yeah
okay wait I have one more thing so
getting back to like let's say advice
for younger generation like what kid
like cuz there's a lot say there's a
young kid listening to this who's like
is on their social media like they're
not even on a point where they're like
they don't they have Valiant excuses of
why they're on their social media or
they're like they're just or even
they're just like dude like I do kinda
wanna get rid of it like I noticed
taking my time I want to work on my
dreams but like I can't like I think so
I taught like a small like for lack of a
better term meditation yoga class but
last week when you guys came over like
so for me can you see can you see how
that helps me pull myself out and like
find my real self and that helps me get
out of the walking around thinking about
what other people are thinking of me it
gets me out of my self-conscious way of
being that the internet culture has now
it's now our normal self-conscious way
of being let's just call that like
you're thinking about what other people
think of you and this meditation yoga
thing that I interest you guys to like
do you do you see the connections like I
was trying to like point out like this
is what it means to find yourself your
intuition like you listen to the real
you yeah and if we can suggest some sort
of like meditation yoga sort of like
like what what can we have kids like in
their basement alone or in their room
alone you have to appeal to what they
like first game there yeah don't go
somewhere you like yeah so you that I
think is important and I think I'm sorry
like obviously studying a lot of
business and consulting and stuff lately
I've been noticing people say like
appeal to what they don't know they want
and that's so true but you have to have
something
something that wraps them in that has
even a little bit of their you have to
enter their world a little bit to get
them to like are you open gate let me
gain your trust right you wouldn't have
this this podcast with some girl you
just met walking through downtown cast
rocky probably would have invited her
yet but maybe you never know yeah I'm
saying well chances are good that your
you invited me because we're comfortable
we're good friends and you trust me you
have some sort of which which opens me
up to be able to listen to your opinion
right right so same same for these kids
probably even more so because you you
know if I if I were an outfit that looks
kind of like the girls are wearing right
now
right you know and I I kind of have some
conversations about things that they
might want to talk about or like even
just like oh yeah I'm listening give
them that attention that's okay you're
speaking to what I like yeah then I can
say my piece and they're there in I've
caught you then not right you know it's
it's got to be outfit that's the thing
is in the the thing is we also forget in
that same sense people find that and
figure it out like oh I figured out the
trick I can't these [__] like the
thing is is humans know truth like we
know we can sense it like we the same
way that when you're on the freeway and
you look over the [__] looks
right back at you yes because we can
sense these things right so if you're
not being truthful in like being like
hey like I'm not gonna pretend to be
this person just cuz it's gonna get to
you guys but like here is a thing that
is a real part of me that I'm going to
word it in form it and paint it in this
way
to where you guys understand so for
example my value right right exactly so
I'm not gonna push it in the face of
people who are not interested yeah
that's a huge thing with me it's like
with this podcast I don't like I don't
talk about social media like I
eventually may start doing like a once a
week poster like I don't know something
but like I don't want it to be forcing
people who don't care about this stuff
to listen to it like it yeah if you want
to if you you you find it if you need it
like okay yeah getting getting them
interested okay so what I've done so
like as a DJ what I do I what they want
is they come up to me so like I do a DJ
a lot of ctsos
and so that's like student conferences
like it'll be like thousands of kids in
like a conference hall in there and
shirt and ties but like they're also
high school kids so yeah you want to
party so they come up in their brat and
play Gucci gang like you know like that
could play that new 2 Chainz song like
they're just saying absurd things to me
that of course I'm never going to in my
professional life play [__] Gucci King
over the intercom at a high school
organization place like so they think
they know what they want right
they absolutely think they know what
they want because if I play Gucci gang
Chad Chad who reaffirms himself as Chad
Master General yeah isn't it when I play
it he can now do this dance yeah like in
in like now Jennifer knows the best job
so like but so so you will accidentally
reaffirm who you think you are if you
keep following all the things so you
need to stop in your tracks and so with
the meditation course the the yoga thing
that I taught you guys I mean I don't
want to take the spark out of it for the
the more that I'll do in the future but
I'll get better at it as I go but I
essentially have them like turn off
themselves in a sentence like it's not
it's not a trick it's not it's me being
my genuine self they all know me they
trust me and I haven't kind of my house
and I have them kind of just shut up and
listen to me for a bit yeah III yeah I
turn I don't I don't allow the audience
to have a say but it's not like you guys
this is what you do you need to follow
the rules I have something to say like
it's I create trust they come here and
they trust me enough to even come here
so that's something that I'm doing right
in life right like a you know I've been
a good friend enough yeah like my you
know like I invite them and I and I try
to I tried intentionally when you guys
got here I try to break down who you
think you are like make you think of
things that you wouldn't think of so you
got here and typically you're probably
thinking I'm gonna walk in we're gonna
do this and you have expectations of
like don't need to bring yoga mat
whatever like one of them one of our
friends brought yoga mat like you got
here and I had a view a basketball and
we started playing pig and I said the
first thing that everybody got here I
said some form of like hey just be
mindful of what you're thinking of today
yeah and I said some form of that to
everybody and like so I didn't take away
these people's time I didn't go to their
house and rip them out and say hey you
be mindful right now I
I offered based off of my information
based off of my like trust like I said
hey here's something I really think you
guys will enjoy and like they can see
the progress in me like they know that
it's true then I'm being truthful yeah
like so I think that the essence of all
these things really has to be something
that you have spent your [__] time in
like who are you to interrupt anybody's
life to tell them to turn off who they
are just because you're like try what I
think yeah and so we're trying to like
shut each other up and like know what I
think is good but like if we can find
ways just of honestly not only trusting
each other but also finding ways to
follow like and stack all of this
knowledge and be like okay how is this
work for other people like so you guys
got here and and we got active when we
got moving we like I would actively try
to engage in this style of conversation
yeah like you'll probably know you
probably would notice cuz it's
supernatural but like we didn't really
talk about other people most of time
like it's we talked about started
hinting at meditation yeah sure
calm anyone if there's an emergency
let's talk about somebody right exactly
your life has a lot more to it and your
brain does a lot more than just gossip
yeah it's funny so the people who are
gossiping there I'm not really gonna
think of they're gossiping like they're
not going to admit like oh my god I'm
just saying it everybody thinks that a
man is a [__] like I'm not I'm not
gossiping like I I mean I'm definitely I
mean so here's the thing as well like I
just did throw up my hands become not
gossiping like we all do that anything
is it's like we're Cosby's [__] man were
gossipy creatures like we want to know
what's going on right okay so what's
gossip so for me I feel like this
podcast we're gonna define a lot of
things gossip is for I guess for me is
like I was talking negatively about a
situation to somebody else who really
didn't need to be in the know sometimes
mm-hmm sometimes it's negative and
sometimes it's like an exciting gossip
like oh my god someone suppose pregnant
they're not gonna tell you how exciting
I'm so glad I know however how did I
find out okay I probably found out from
somebody who said right does that make
it about that's I'm saying so there is a
negative connotation with it does happen
to be negative though because because
but just saying like hey did you
here that that this person is pregnant
like that's not that's talking about
someone else certainly and it makes it
makes us feel weird right well how are
you talking about I can actually
actually can hear you yeah where are all
these names I have a lot of names today
I don't know any of these people my
sister's name is Ashley she's super
friendly but she's pretty cool yeah we
have we have these like negative I gave
up on that one connotation of gossip
yeah negative connotation of gossip so
that doesn't mean that like just cuz
you're saying someone's pregnant just
cuz you're talking about other people
but but I think that talking about other
people as in whatwhat's the newest news
on someone else is gossip doesn't have
to be negative you have to be like did
you hear that Cynthia's dad like hooked
up with with Amanda's mom like what like
it doesn't have to be negative
it was elaborate - it doesn't have to be
negative but it's like wasting your
valuable 100 slots a day in the 24 hours
but so you don't get to form new
neurological pathways when [__]
Jennifer's moms gossip is in your brain
so what do you do every day to get away
from that stuff so because the bottom
line is these are things you may not
know that you're doing or are taking up
your time until you're able to step back
so you know we talked about information
overload right such a common thing so
what if we learn all this stuff
typically like I don't learn my gossip
from from social media
I learned my gossip by like seeing it on
social media and asking a friend who
might know right so I don't think that's
absolutely right so if I see it on
social media I'm like I don't know if I
can believe that or whatever I don't
know but I'm gonna go to my second
source here and I'm gonna find out and
then what they told me is like oh I
found that out but it doesn't actually
affect me so I'm just gonna I'm here
came in and a little bit but like it
doesn't actually I don't need it but I'm
gonna I'm gonna just let it out later
yeah we feel like we need to do
something with it yeah we recognize that
it's not [__] ours and we need to put
it somewhere yeah where we need to put
it is just let it go or say say it like
I don't know why you're taking a poop
and nobody's listening to your see yeah
see my [__] dogs you
yeah as you're taking a poop just like
damn y'all here Jennifer's pregnant yeah
and then you stop when you listen that
you're like damn what a waste of like
why don't anybody like we don't even
know that we're gonna know when she has
a baby when we see her next that'll be
fine we'll see the baby in a year we
don't have to think about her ever again
until a year was here bashing your name
do you think that do you think the
information has been held up so highly
valuable to us that we think all
information is important yeah yeah
everything we learn is accidentally
important though yeah
which it is it is sure whatever but if
it's what you but does it to be the most
important yeah what does it do for your
life yeah what is it so so if these kids
are out gossiping like what so what what
can they do better in their life so like
next time maybe just hearing this
conversation maybe they can stop and be
like oh [__] I am talking about Cynthia
again yeah like or Oh Joey just walked
up to me I'm gonna tell him all about
Stephanie's mom like maybe you're gonna
have this little inch this little let's
call it intuition as a spark of joy
little seed that'll say like Jennifer's
whoever I said like but so the thing is
I'm not kidding if you start listening
to the little voice and you just don't
say it like it's okay to be in silence
where you can wait for them to talk or
if they talk and they're like hey did
you hear about Jennifer you could be
like oh cool and you could change the
subject like you can really yeah so it's
so interject there's like a little voice
before your thoughts of just saying [__]
out loud and you could interject and the
way so that voice is very very weak in
people who are never alone if you are
never ever alone if you even if you're
codependent like even if you had a
terrible I I think that I think of that
by human nature so I've actually thought
about this very intricately so are you
saying intuition is intuition exists
with the network I would say yeah that
little boy I sorry I'm gonna say are you
saying intuition
yeah people say like so you're saying
I've had I've had this I think very
indefinitely like through intuition so
if we're all of the earth like we're not
like we didn't come from like we weren't
born on Mars and we took some spaceship
somebody got on earth really all right
how do we feel like we're literally like
as far as we know our best our best bet
is that we crew I mean this is like our
truth this is what we know evolution we
grew those years like evolution created
humans like after turn we are of the
earth so if you took away time we are
equally the same [__] thing that Iraq
is like from this thing that's the earth
forever yeah and the so an intuition
what an intuition means to me is all
these things have their job so like my
liver knows how to be livery like it
does delivery things like I'm not
consciously processing this beer I'm not
consciously processing this like I'm not
saying this is bad let's put it here
like mrs. P this is poop like nothing
that poop goes through everybody yeah no
but like so the things the process of
our body of a human's body and of the
world knows what to do without
it's an intuition yeah so society and
what happens from society so from
society we've now created these this
terrible thing of like kids stuck and
set the second stage of what we went
through like which was amazing but it
also has terrible imitations like they
don't know that before yeah yes so they
may not know their intuition so I think
yeah so I think that it may be our duty
and I'm not even just saying this
podcast like I literally I think this
may be it may be a poopy to to to really
like say like holy [__] like we
accidentally robbed these kids of
feeling the feeling of a gut the kid
ourselves - yeah and I've had a break
because we don't want to feel [__] well
no we just have never when you have when
you have social media or you have
technology or you have whatever it like
we were saying when you go on a trip and
I go to vacation if I'm like okay I've
looked at this thing on Pinterest a
million times we've got to be beautiful
and you get there and you're in your
it's game effects aren't applied to it
yeah and it's it's too real I feel
that's pretty and that's all you got
because you don't get this aw moment and
it's it's the same with with life in
general like this is the what if I would
leave you know the world ever given
advice to it 11 12 year old kid it's
take some time to walk outside and
breathe in the fresh air see the grass
you know hear it
feel the wind like literally use all of
your senses maybe even not maybe even
take your sight away for a while you
know I mean give yourself the idea of
like functioning mm-hmm yeah like
meditative sorts and so yeah well I mean
I mean see what feels right to you
there's not really like it's not like
you go outside and you're like looking
at this list that you just wrote down
right like you're like okay they said go
sign okay fill your senses okay okay
like so so what this means what this
means to mean like this is leading back
to what what I was talking about that
little meditation yoga class I taught is
I really was just trying to shut who you
who you need to do you think you need to
be or who you think others think you are
off and in really like for lack of a
better word forced presence on you like
or actually no awakened the presence
that's already in you like and so I sat
there and we went through some
meditations but essentially all you need
to do to do this yourself let's say is
just just sit down and commit to
whatever you gonna do like whether
that's I'm gonna listen to this person
or I'm gonna try this two-minute
meditation or whatever and you turn your
phone in airplane mode you turn it off
or you leave it inside you put music on
whenever you got to do go outside and
just be with whatever you're thinking
about right like just just get outside
yeah like and so here's the thing is if
you've never been taught this before so
Jessica I'm afraid that when you say go
outside in pee with the grass and smell
the air like I don't think I don't think
that these kids know how to do what that
mean so so what I mean by that that
there is as is a human nature and I'm
not even trying to be whoohoo about this
this is there's an incredible you can
feel right yeah it is though just
because I mean I'm saying these things
based off of who I used to be who vs.
who I am now like there there is I
promise you just completely sober you
can go outside and just really after
some experience smell the air and and
look at the beautiful trees and and and
feel like you're actually a part of
something like you don't feel like like
you know you see you're talking like a
homeless person who feels like they
don't have that underlying layer like
you can feel that thing just a part of
being alive like being a part of the
earth is that your welcoming yeah you
can and so so go outside and so this is
something that like you can't do this
wrong you can't do this there's not
really been doing right like this is
just being who you are without any input
so don't don't try to like what would I
do or like oh how would I say or or how
do what does it mean to smell like just
go inside just start smelling and then
there shouldn't be any confinement yeah
because I think we that's the thing a
lot of rules a little yeah I mean that's
really look at what religious did we
literally read the [__] we think that
it's a metaphysical book and we're like
well you should drink the body of Christ
so we'd make wine like dude it's weird
like yeah these are all we don't need
anything right but no don't things these
aren't literal things these are there's
something that you have potential of
feeling like if these things seem like
they're you have something real like I
had like my life could maybe be better
like maybe it's not something maybe I
should go walk outside for comment yeah
there's something that for me personally
I felt as a 27 year old man that I had I
don't think or maybe I had forgot about
it that I hadn't felt as a kid that I
had ever felt before like this is a
profound like a presence true presence
had been taken from me I'm not here to
blame the internet right I understand it
now yeah but I mean I'm saying like I
was in a let's say a blind like I was
very depressed for five years let's say
yeah like I was in a blindness of of
course I knew I was depressed and I was
a sad [__] but like this sentence
wouldn't make sense
someone's a go outside just breathe air
it'll make you feel better I'm like you
are stupid that's not how things work
you don't understand my blah blah yeah
I'm and I'm this and you don't know what
the pressure is like I'm telling you you
don't need to know the answer to this
and you're not looking for an answer
here's the thing you're not looking for
an answer go outside and breathe the air
pressure breathe you breathe the fresh
air look around the trees and don't have
your phone out don't have if you're
gonna have music in your phone like go
to Spotify shuffle meditation yoga or
whatever no no please no words and this
something from a DJ in a music person
like I love music and I'm always shoving
music John my ears and podcasters go out
and be with only or thoughts I would say
I need a little bit of background music
if I can help and I enjoy background
music but just like peaceful piano or
meditation yoga and just walk around
yeah in and watch what you think about
don't watch what you think about as an
observer try not to do anything but just
don't change don't change where you're
at or what you're doing yeah just follow
away like this is something that I had a
really hard time with but then it took I
guess a good yoga teacher and then also
like Adrian yoga with Adriene oh yeah
she's grateful I really love when when
someone who's teaching you because
usually if you're teaching the goal is
get this right do this right right
that's what we've learnt I loved I don't
remember where I want to say like hellos
maybe on Commerce in Longview I think
that's where I really the first so
that's a you that yoga studio yoga
studio yeah what's it called oh no solos
hol OS I'll check it out and we I did
hot yoga with one of my girlfriends
who's also super super like encouraging
and understanding not judgmental and
really not I mean she's really a huge
person that I needed at the time and we
went to yoga together and I was like I'm
doing this wrong whoever and the lady
said like not even maybe like 40 seconds
after I had thought had that thought and
was like about to like quit the move we
were doing she was like you cannot do
this wrong and I was just like thank God
dude it feel like I don't like it's so
funny I feel like they could say that
multiple times in like suddenly it
clicked with with Adriene like it was
something and I I kept repeating with
you guys too in the
little thing I did like it's something
that we literally think we're so social
media trains you and like even our
political system like our whole society
like it's terrible to use we're cited so
often but we've kind of actually been
trained that everything needs an end
like everything like you're doing this
you can get to this you yes thank you
like here yeah here's the thing is like
dude you're not wrong like these things
you have like everything's that I'm
crazy but like I think that this is
right you're not wrong at all what you
think is right as maybe is right that's
okay like you can feel that way
you've got a coincide fighting what you
think is right outwardly it's not how
you do it you got to come sort of what's
right inside and then you live your life
according to how how does this what I
think work out of here one and what is
so III keep poking up like I really want
to get it through to anybody listening
young kids especially of like they're
not going to see like what what is the
point of going outside and just walking
in 20 minutes okay so you think it's
something that like okay so there's
something that we commonly say like if
you coincide and you just please don't
talk to any like don't don't walk with a
friend
don't bring music just go outside and
just listen and walk or sit or something
for iam and it's like you think like
that's enough to make them experience
like that's what they're talking about
or do you think we need to like do they
need to be thinking about certain things
or going to just watch what they're
thinking about like for the youth I
would say just getting them to make the
decision themselves to go outside right
because they are very much in the like
I'm not gonna do that if I don't have to
mm-hmm nobody wants to be the first
person on the dance floor they've always
got to wait for one person to go out
there first
I wouldn't I think I think it would come
with like the that mindset of like how
is this gonna immediately make me feel
better and if you can't give me a
legitimate reason right you you can't
make me like understand the feeling
right here right now I'm not going dude
I don't want to go to work to make money
I don't work overtime if I don't have to
are really not gonna directly benefit me
yeah so I think it has to be something
cuz to be really fair
I'm that way I'm very much like I don't
want to make a cheese quesadilla on the
stove oh yeah yeah I don't want to make
a cheese quesadilla on the stove and I
don't want to add any meat and make it
like so good that I could make it home
because I want it right now I'm hungry
and I I don't care if it tastes that
great I want it yeah so if it doesn't
directly benefit me and it takes me 15
minutes that's why cooking is so hard
because I was like holy [__] it's gonna
take me 45 minutes to make this meal
right and I'm in it and I'm gonna eat it
in one minute
I don't mindfully eat it at that point
that point I'm just done with it
and do you think the instant
gratification robbed you of the I mean
the essence of having a grilled cheese
is kind of the fact that you have enough
free time that you chose your job well
enough - we have enough free time in
your nice apartment with your husband
with you or whatever like to enjoy a
grilled cheese sandwich you're gonna put
some peppers on it you're gonna do like
it's the essence of the the because
because time is not who can have the
most time ever and you win there's no
winning in life you thought we all die
this is all taken from a student like
yeah so time is is it so if you can get
to a point where you can enjoy from
point A to point Z not just a a - like
I'm a and then I need to get to Z right
[__] now if you enjoyed the letters
in between by like I like cooking this
and enjoy my house is nice so if you can
go outside and be like oh I'm able to
like walk around on sound like that's
that's pretty cool like oh this is nice
you start to notice things you
appreciate and then it replaces all
these thoughts that you have every day
of like Jesse's [__] mom and Jesse's
mom exactly like just all these thoughts
that you've been filled with by your
phone by school by all these just life
just like just yeah and yeah it started
yeah I mean I I do have you know that's
not with the exception of snapchat and
then I have a facebook that's just for
my work I have to keep up on it but I
don't actually have like but anyway I
feel like without social media I have
enough I have information overload right
so it's bizarre to me that
at my time with that other people's
information it's crazy because now that
I'm done with school and it's been a
long time since I've been like done with
school not worked a job that stresses me
out or makes me feel like I have to
devote my entire brain to it I'm having
time again to go and do the things that
I want to do and make myself and I'm
finally in this place where I'm like I
feel like I have free time yeah it has
been so you know he's doing right and
even on you know even on my days off
from work I'm going I'm doing this I'm
making sure this is done having this
done this is done this is here making
sure I see this 14 people in 24 hours
because I have to because I haven't seen
them in a company obligations almost
yeah I peel that away dude and I was
thinking you know I think like tomorrow
oh I don't work till 3:00 and you know
Tyler's not going home until 11:00 or
12:00 so I have just like all right so
so what do you like what's your like so
you're going to use just because I'm in
you are you're gonna use that like
that's you time like it's Jessica time
just like what what are your plans and
like just in terms of like how could
other people create their own instead of
watching Netflix when you get a couple
minutes instead of going on social media
instead of smoking cigarette instead of
like whatever these things that don't
really seem to be doing anything but
killing time yeah like or or really if
it's on your phone let's just eliminate
that it's like how do you like are you
just like what are you what's your day
look like tomorrow well your free time I
mean in general yeah so I like to start
my morning with like making my coffee
I've been making cappuccinos for myself
isn't something and it's like a just one
of my favorite things and I finally
started making them for myself in the
morning at my house and then I'm sitting
down on the couch typically with the
dogs because I you know yes they slept
in our bedroom or in our bed but I
didn't like pay attention to them all
night so I wake up and we are just going
yeah we have like time where I get to
like hang out with my dogs and drink my
coffee on the occasion I read a book on
my phone or whatever but I also like I
know I want to learn to play the guitar
the other thing is I'm not putting
pressure on learning guitar
yeah what's the point in learning if
you're drilling it like it's not about
being able to play guitar it's like
learning to play guitar the word
learning it's like the coolest part
because you like can't pattern over time
up the guitar right now sitting with the
guitar for 10 minutes prick plucking at
the strings and pretending and hearing
the sounds mm-hmm six months yeah I am
still getting myself like it's a slow
process but it's going it's killing that
instant gratification bug to like the
Instagram efficacious were like I wanted
to and my perfectionism yeah because you
there's no right and wrong with what
you're doing you're just experiencing
life like your III don't I know I'm not
I'm gonna pick up his car and I'm I'm
not good at it dang that sucks you just
put it down you never try it again
no you crunch I say this like half
heartedly half joking earlier when we
were talking about me having 27 jobs hmm
I quit things when I'm when I'm done
with them and I do it you know I react
on emotions a lot of the time I would
say in my past the other thing is I act
based on like I am NOT happy doing this
job I refuse to continue doing it and
usually by the point that I've quit I've
tried multiple ways or I've like went to
work and been like okay I'm gonna enjoy
this today how can I make this better so
I went through the motions of like
making things better yeah talk to
yourself about it right right knows you
don't know what you think until you talk
to yourself
right but I I'm a badly working to be
better about not quitting things
immediately because they're hard soccer
is a great example I am a phenomenal
coach I would be a phenomenal coach I
know the field I know the plays I know
the dynamics I know the logistics I
could tell you when there's a great
player I can tell you what positions you
should be in when I'm on the field
myself I am only good to be the bully
and I say that because I chose to
disregard the hard parts of my summer of
getting in shape and actually like
working on snow moment I know I'm a
great shooter and I don't have strong
legs and I'm a you know I can run the
whole game right I never never never
never would go home and work on footwork
by myself because
was afraid I was gonna break my ankle
yeah I knew I wasn't good at it and it
was hard and I didn't even know where to
start and I never looked on YouTube when
I was 16 I didn't think about it that
wasn't thing well that's why I'm saying
I didn't look for skills I didn't try to
like learn how to make myself better so
I learned unexpected team better right
you know by being this I was good the
funny one or the inspirational Werner
whatever and that's totally cool I'm
glad with that but over this last I want
to say year has probably been a pretty
good learning curve for me because I was
able to quit a job that I absolutely was
just like stuck in I was able to do a
lot of things well that's here for a
whole finger biz like yeah it has been
pretty like wow life-changing and I
think now I'm kind of getting to the
point where I'm mentally fighting that
fight and a lot of it you know not a lot
of it I can't I can't credit all that
Tyler does a really good job of being
like that's your mentality saying that
that is not you are not incapable like
the Tyler is is saying you're so capable
you're saying it as an absolute it's not
yeah and he's saying break down that
wall like I can't run three miles but
are you kidding me okay what he is built
to run okay but but so I think I think
is that's obviously that's very
important I totally agree but I think
that what does take what is being taken
away is like what like someone is really
gonna say even as a joke like even if
like this gives to be on someone's
[__] joking Instagram mean page of
like recording this and being like me
after I hear that like go out [__] I
wanna do that when I eat chips and I
don't like so like I'm inserting like
comedy is a good way to like read it on
that boat of like self shame and let
that happen but like like how do we I'm
afraid that people are going to stop
with why would I do that when I could
just eat chips like why would I push
myself what is the volume there's
genuine genuinely I think that people
have never ever experienced like their
inner selves like triumphantly winning
something or like and I'm I'm talking
more like a trophy or whatever like I'm
talking about like oh [__] this is
something that I single-handedly worked
very hard on and I feel the like this
may be a better man like there's evil
how do people and I think a lot of
people because of the Internet
who have never felt this before there's
there's there's 30 years older 40 years
old there's 13 year olds who have never
felt this like this is an experience of
like wonder of like yeah of I don't
think I could run four miles and then
you run four miles and you're like oh
[__] and then other people around you
are like to him he ran four miles I'm
the same age as him he's like only
install I don't have a groom for miles
I'm like what I'm saying like no these
people like I think yeah yeah it's so
they've never felt yeah so they only see
the obstacles like why would I do that
because I'm saying the why of why we do
anything is it
there isn't an answer to that yeah I
don't think I think that why we do
everything is the essence of doing
everything the the journey of life is
really just a journey I don't even think
I don't even know like what's going on
at the end of life or like I think it's
just a journey like the essence of why
do you do anything is to get better yeah
right yeah how can you eat in the tunnel
how can you floss on the tunnel yeah
they said they or like or even outside
of that like just to tend on a mystical
being part like what is the tunnel no no
not what what is in the tunnel not how
about what is it tunnel why are we
talking about
who put the tunnel there come back next
week junkyard love podcast no let's
let's wrap it up the Jessica fall what
is a fowler fall let's let's settle that
anybody on the internet we could do that
[__] do like like the Internet has
created these two different last name
worlds and first names like your name
starts with an N but it ends with like
seven GS
nobody knows they make up words in their
head so is it fall or foul just to fall
well okay I'm gonna solve this age-old
familial battle okay we say foul because
it's German the AU in Germany
in German languages ow right so foul may
you espouse however I have a as my dad
has always explained it rich side of my
family who calls themselves the Falls so
really like separating themselves yeah
yes
so the fouls were the ones who didn't
have money and the Falls were the rich
family see I wonder like how much of
that like like how does that look is
that real do they really think that do
they think they're any better than you
well that that's the thing is when
people meet me and they know any of the
falls
they say are you related to so-and-so
fall and I'll say yeah because yeah yeah
of course yeah they relate to like if
you have that last name it's it's not
common it's not a common last name I
don't know anybody else in the frickin
world of where we live in the
environment that I'm not related to that
house that name it's not like a Jones or
you know it's nothing like that it's not
just its common last name so I'm always
like yes and I never correct people
because personally I don't give a [__]
dude yeah why like people like it's
Rihanna it's like it doesn't matter at
all like those are things we just took
our 100 memory slots and we filled
[__] one of them with you correcting
me on Rihanna Rihanna like but I used to
do the same thing so I know I literally
used to go on my way to correct people
and they said the wrong form of your or
you are which granted language is
important and we shouldn't really just
throw it around like get it together but
I used to correct it so jessica foul or
fall whichever you'd like we're fufu but
what is searching your junk yard if
you're 27 years of life like not just
what you've learned recently like what
you've learned in life like what is
something like if you if you had to
leave behind like when you leave this
world like what's uh what's something
that you want that's where you can leave
it alright thank you ladies and
gentlemen
we'll just loop that for four hours and
that will be the outro of this
meditation yeah and your meditate that's
your that's your chance
that's your channel yeah your mantra is
just
what would you like to leave behind like
what's something you were gosh I don't
know I what's important for other people
to know from you that you've learned get
to know people yeah get to and do it in
their in their way on the way that you
know the way that they like do it how
live in their world yeah really
like listen I guess is the thing because
you if you get to know someone you're
not doing the talking you're you're
hearing them if I ever leave this world
behind if I ever leave this world behind
if I ever leave this world behind
[Laughter]
you